<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/</link><image><url>https://configure-able.info/lib/media/favicon.svg</url><title>Configure-Able Infrastructures</title><link>https://configure-able.info/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:35:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://configure-able.info/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:34:50 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[George Simms]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>George Simms</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[(¬_¬)/` Serv(er)ing In-grid]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br><br>In this workshop I aim for us to think about how we make and imagine collective places of infrastructure. In this exchange we will materially and technically setup a server space, and along that journey together we will ask questions and discuss&nbsp;how we want to practice these technologies collectively.<br>The end goal is to have collectively edited set of protocols or a manifesto that we publish to an html page on the server.<br><br><br>Material for this workshop was developed from collaborative work over a number of iterations from projects including servpub, collective infrastructures and cozy-cloud.<br>Outcomes from this workshop will also be used in my PhD as well as published in the new Servus journal? (I think it is) And I will make sure we are all credited!<br><br><br>This workshop and the server are hosted by Servus in Linx Austria. They are an artist run data centre and have given us this space to practice our own network tech and projects. It is run on hydro electric energy and hosts a number of other collectives, tech enthusiasts and artists.<br><br><br><br>We will be making and editing a manifesto of sorts as we work through the steps of this workshop. <br>These will be hosted on an html file on the server, and is accessible at this URL page: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io/" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io/</a><br><br><br>When it comes to making collaborative community driven sociotechnical infrastructure, there is always a complex network of relations that we have to work through. Negotiating every relation when we enter a space could be very complex and time consuming, as we will see, but setting protocols helps us firm up ways of working and relational conventions that ease this flow. Through setting these protocols together we mean to disobey the norms of network infrastructures and actively re-scope how we come to these systems and relations together.<br><br><br><img alt="A diagram that shares the collectives that make up the Servpub project, from In-grid, to Creative-Crowds, Systerserver, UCL LSBU and Arhus." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" target="_self"><br><br><br>Relating to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" target="_self">original feminist server manifesto</a> by some of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://constantvzw.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://constantvzw.org/" target="_self">Constant</a>. Manifesting and imagining what a feminist server is and does.<br>A feminist server…&nbsp; * Is a situated technology. She has a sense of context and considers herself to be part of an ecology of practices
* Is run for and by a community that cares enough for h
er in order to make her exist
* Builds on the materiality of software, hardware and the bodies gathered around it
* Opens herself to expose processes, tools, sources, habits, patterns
* Does not strive for seamlessness. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible
* Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be traps
* Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous and parasitic practice
* Is autonomous in the sense that she decides for her own dependencies
* Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; experiments with changing client-server relations where she can
* Treats network technology as part of a social reality
* Wants networks to be mutable and read-write accessible
* Does not confuse safety with security
* Takes the risk of exposing her insecurity
* Tries hard not to apologize when she is sometimes not available
<br><br><br>Manifesto = Man x Infest<br>
Infest being the taking hold of and grasping threateningly at things as proof! <br>Femfester = Feminism x Fistula<br>
Fistula being part of an festering, a pipeline with many holes. Thinking of a patchwork infra!
<br>We can change this, it was just me having fun with wordz.<br><br><br><br><br>You can have a lot of passwords and bits here, so I use a password manager like <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://keepassxc.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://keepassxc.org/" target="_self">Keypassxc</a><br><br><br>Lets give a little context of working with computers.<br><br><br>So most people are probably used to working through a graphical user interface (GUI), which is a relatively recent way of interfacing with a computer. This is great for accessibility but also tends to scope and direct the abilities and capacities you have on your computer, as in there are only so many buttons or things you can show in a communicable way. <br><br><br><img alt="A screenshot of a terminal interface with the Echo command used to write out &quot;Howdy&quot;" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/howdyterminal.png" target="_self"><br>Terminal is a more classic way of working with a machine, and roughly speaking is the step between punch-card/magnetic tape style computing and a GUI. It is a very simple but powerful interface that lets you run basically any command on your system through a text interface. Compared to a GUI this space is more "risky" as you can do anything from anywhere, such as deleting the entire operating system (not advised). It also means that there are no limitations to your system administration so you have access to a granular level of working. <br><br><br>Prompt
When entering into this more "risky" space on a computer network, it is good to set some intentions and work out how to move through this space with care. As we go though these next steps getting into terminal have a think about what it means to be in this place of power/risk, and what relations you think you need to care for in the formation of these protocols?
It can also be a great place to think about if/how the relations of a system enables you to perform this role of power, and what change in relations this new role brings with it. <br><br><br>This depends on your platform, so...<br><br><br>On a Mac it is already installed! So all you need to do is:<br>
<br>Search up Terminal
<br>Open it!
<br><br><br>There are similar programs to terminal already installed, but not the same language (bash). There are a few ways to do this, but I recomend installing an ubuntu vm shell for bash, as it gives the most capability for this use case:<br>
<br>Install the VM from the windows store <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9PDXGNCFSCZV?ocid=pdpshare" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9PDXGNCFSCZV?ocid=pdpshare" target="_self">HERE</a>and remember your password!
<br>Then open it up!
<br><br><br>As we said before terminal is a text/syntax-based way of interfacing your machine and we are going to introduce a few basic commands and concepts to get us going today.<br><br><br>Let's simply use echo to get our terminal to say HI!.<br>To do this use:<br>echo &lt;message&gt;
<br>e.g.<br>echo HI!
<br><br><br>Now lets see who your computer!<br>Show the name of the currently logged in user:<br>whoami
<br>Show the name of the machine is given on the network:<br>hostname
<br><br><br>Much of working on the command line involves navigating around your system without the use of a Graphical User Interface (GUI).<br>However, we will essentially be navigating around normal computer folder hierarchies like below:<br>root/
├─ directoryname/ ├─ anotherdirectory/ ├─ aFileName.txt
<br><br>Directory&nbsp;: also known as a folder<br>Print working directory that you are currently in:<br>pwd
<br>List current directory contents:<br>ls
<br><br><br>Now to move between directories/folders we use cd like so<br>cd &lt;directory_name&gt;
<br>e.g.<br>cd folder1
<br>
We can use a folder that was shown with ls in the last step!<br>
You can also check whats in the new folder with ls to see that you have moved.
<br><br><br>Prompt
In this potentially unfamiliar space how do we keep track of where we are, what we've done &amp; what commands we may need in the future?
Basically how do we want to orient ourselves?
<br><br><br>Secure Shell (SSH) is a way of working on another machine from your own, working in their shell (bash). <br>It basically lets you work on another computers terminal remotely. This is the way you will work on most servers or remote/faceless computers (computers without a screen).<br><br><br><img alt="Diagram showing how these devices are connected and communicate over the internet and via the SSH protocol." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/sshdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br>The SSH protocol enables us to talk securely to our server by encrypting and authenticating all of our communication/interfacing through the network. <br>Traditionally tech has a metaphor of SSH as a secure hand shake protocol, but it will be great to think about what metaphor or relation we want when it comes to crossing boundaries and into shared spaces. <br>Do we want to hand shake or do we think . . . would enable . . . <br><br><br>Again this may be a bit different on different systems, as some will have this already installed and some will need to install it. <br>Install it with:<br>sudo apt install openssh-client
<br>If you are on gitbash on windows, it should be installed.<br><br><br>To SSH into the Server with servus we need to use their IP!<br>An IP address is basically the postcode/address we will find the pi at on the network.<br>The IP for our Servus server is:<br>
193.170.194.204<br>But we also have it as a named server:<br>
vps.in-grid.io<br><br><br>Now that we have the IP address, any computer can request to SSH into the server through these commands:<br>ssh &lt;user_name&gt;@&lt;ip&gt;
<br>eg.<br>ssh in-grid@193.170.194.204
<br>or<br>ssh in-grid@vps.in-grid.io
<br>You are now "logging into" our server, so it will ask for the password here and that I will share with you.<br><br><br>You should now see your terminal username change from your laptop's local user to something like: <br>in-grid@vps:~$ <br>If you want to exit out of the pi (we don't atm) type:<br>exit
<br>Hit enter. You will need to have exited the pi before setting up your ssh key. <br><br><br>Prompt
How do we navigate another machine through our own "interface"?<br>
What are the relational agreements to being on this other machine?
<br><br><br>Sudo enables us to take on a superuser role.<br>
This means that we have all the security permissions for that system. This is a "very risky" role, as here you can do anything on the server/computer. With sudo you can actually delete the entire system or make other similar drastic commands, but it also means that we have the ability to manage and configure our system to our needs.<br>When we come to writing protocols for sudo, what does it mean for us to be a "superuser" or an admin, and what care and consideration should we take on in these protocols?<br><br><img alt="Diagram shares how different users can connect to systems with different permissions and access levels." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br><br>To become sudo or root you just need to:<br>sudo su
<br>And then enter the password when prompted.<br><br><br>Prompt
Super User can Do! a lot... what permissions are we comfortable navigating?<br>
How intimate are we with our machines?
<br><br><br>Caring for a server includes routine tasks like updating/upgrading the system software, tiding up files, creating new users &amp; giving access permissions, paying attention to errors and bug reports.<br>We are going to initiate this server by making us all users!<br><br><img alt="Diagram showing all of the connections within the Servpub Infrastructure. It shares how devices are connected through a VPN and server to host things online." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/connectionsdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br><br>To make a new user, use the command below. Note, that you will be prompted to input a password and it is always better to give different users passwords<br>adduser &lt;nameofuser&gt;
<br><br><br>If you want to give this user sudo access, then they have to be added to the "sudo" group. You don't need to create this group, it exists by default and you can just add or remove users from it. The sudo group is stored in this directory: /etc/sudoers.d/<br>usermod -aG sudo &lt;nameofuser&gt;
<br>You can check to see who is in the group sudo using this command:<br> grep '^sudo:.*$' /etc/group
<br><br><br>Now you can change into the new user (in other words, sign into their account):<br>su &lt;nameofuser&gt;
<br><br><br>You could also log in now with:<br>ssh &lt;username&gt;@193.170.194.204
<br>or<br>ssh &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
<br>And log in with the password you just added.<br><br><br>Prompt
How can we re-imagine users to something less explicit and more gentle?<br>
How do we want to configure the imaginaries to these roles?
<br><br><br>SSH Keys are user specific and are used in addition to a shared login password. To make this method of access truly secure we will need to eventually disable password-only login.<br>
<br>
The shared password is the Lock, and the private password is the Key. Keys are non-transferable and have to be generated per user. <br>Make sure you are back on your own system with:<br>exit
<br>Then to generate the keys, call this command: <br>ssh-keygen -t rsa
<br>Fill in the information requested (note: most of it is optional so you can leave it blank) and set a password (not optional).<br><br><br>The shared key is the:<br>id_rsa.pub<br>and the private Key is the:<br>id_rsa <br>Make note of the path to your id_rsa.pub, we'll need it in the next step.<br><br><br>The public, Lock, password now needs to be copied over to the raspberry pi. Do this via this command (replacing the first bracket with the path to the id_rsa.pub, and the second to the Pis IP address, which we found earlier):<br>ssh-copy-id -i &lt;path to id_rsa.pub&gt; &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
<br>Enter password to complete transfer.<br><br><br>I find it easiest to login with the key linked directly.<br>sudo ssh -i &lt;path/to/id_rsa.pub&gt; &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
<br>Note
Maybe check you can become sudo with sudo su
<br><br><br>Only do this after everyone who need to access the server has uploaded their Keys!<br>It is also recommended that you keep one person ssh'd in at all times during testing this, so if you do something wrong you can unlock it again.<br>Access the config file by:<br>sudo nano -l /etc/ssh/sshd_config
<br><br>And in uncomment 'PasswordAuthentication' on line 57 and set to 'no', then save and exit:<br>PasswordAuthentication no
<br>Then restart the SSH connection:<br>sudo service ssh restart
<br><br><br>Keep someone logged in at all times!<br>Have someone else log out and back in, trying with a password which should fail, and then the key which should work!<br><br><br>Prompt
Now this server is "safe" and secure, can we reflect on what that means to us?<br>
How do we imagine this server being a safe space beyond SSH keys?
<br><br><br>Tmux is what is called a multiplexer, which is a software that lets us collectively work one terminal session. <br>This is how many collectives and collaborative networks work together on servers in one space. It lets us edit and run commands in one space and take responsibility and practice our infra becoming together.<br>When we come to writing protocols we might want to think about what it means to be one user together, and how can we keep everyone at the same pace and comfortable levels of understanding. <br><br><br>All become sudo with:<br>sudo su
<br>Now we are all sudo we can initiate a shared session to work in together.<br>To do this we use:<br>tmux new -s &lt;session name&gt;
<br>e.g. <br>tmux new -s in-sesh
<br>Now we need to name our collective space. If we think back*forward in this workshop, what are the intentions, dynamics and relations we want to collectively name this space with?<br><br><br>Now we have an active session we can join it by just typing:<br>tmux a -t in-sesh
<br>
Rember we have to be sudo to join this!
<br><br><br>Now we can say hi to one another and say cute messages in the space by:<br>echo &lt;message&gt;
<br>Say something to welcome each other into this session, you may need to take turns.<br><br><br>As we saw even each of us writing an echo command takes a little bit of choreographing. When this gets more complicated, like writing complex configuration files, you can imagine it gets even more tricky.<br>Prompt
So here we need to think about how we might manage collective editing. What operational metaphor might we use to describe the relationship between the person typing and the others? Who and how do we choose to type? How do we take care of every voice in that conversation?
<br><br><br>We've created a simple html document to edit. We need to navigate to that file, open and edit it. <br>First lets navigate to the folder its inside and list its contents.<br>cd /var/www/femfester
ls
<br>We should see a file called:<br>index.html`<br><br><br>Now we are in the right folder we can edit the file with nano which is a terminal base text editor. <br>To open the file with nano we do:<br>nano index.html
<br>This will open the file in the terminal.<br><br><br><img alt="A screenshot capturing a bright pink terminal interface which has the HTML page we are editing shown in nano. Nano is a basic text editor based in the terminal." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/nanoofhtml.png" target="_self"><br>Tip
Being terminal you have to navigate with the keyboard, and also copy and past by right clicking (not "CNTRL+C/P")
<br><br><br>From here we can then add text and images using basic HTML syntax.<br>For the time being we are going to just add fun bits to see it work, as we have some more protocols to write and add.<br>So for now add a message or paste in some ascii art with the help of these links:<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" target="_self">ascii text gen</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" target="_self">ascii image gen</a><br>Remember to paste in with a right click!<br><br><br>Now if we return to the file online at:<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io</a><br>we will see our beautiful inputs.<br><br><br>prompt
How do we negotiate the space of working collectively as one user?<br>
What other considerations need to be voiced?
<br><br><br>When we finish up working together there are lots of things we can do to make it easier to return to our work, make it legible to others, as well as caring for the infrastructure we're working in. This could include careful documentation, understanding how to save and record edits, and exiting programs in their nuanced ways.<br><br><br>We've finished working together and now we would like to leave our TMUX session. This is a little more complex than it might appear. Leaving a session using an 'exit' command will delete the session for others, and you will lose the record of your edits together. Instead we can either:<br>Close the entire terminal session window, or use Ctrl-b. This will retain the terminal session for you to use again in the future. <br><br><br>Let's consider collectively how to ensure we exit safely, using a door rather than an ejector seat. How does this action differ from exiting other softwares and how does this attention affect our relationships.<br>prompt
How can we form protocols that enable us to care for who is coming next and which <br><br><br>Now we have all the protocols ready lets add them to the HTML file with nano again.<br>Once we have edited the HTML, we can launch our page in a browser! <br>At <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io/" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io/</a><br><br><br>Practising infrastructuring collectively can be (intentionally) a slow, careful and unscalable process, so it's important to acknowledge our incremental changes, achievements and presence. <br><br><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self">Our (ongoing) documentation</a><br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/entries/serving-in-grid-workshop-slides.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/entries/Serving In-grid Workshop slides.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:44:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Improvised Captions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This page shares the improvised automated caption setup that was made and shared for the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshops</a>. Alongside this is also shared here how the different FLOSS video call and automated caption software we tried and that lacked the capacities that was wanted for the workshop.<br><br>It does have to be said that even with this desire to manifest FLOSS access, the improvised automated captions we came up with still ended up working with big tech solutions. In discussion we felt working here with google's local automated caption on a FLOSS video call was a way to Wiggle Room towards access within FLOSS. Even though this approach also did ask individuals to configure their own access, we tried to offer up interdependent access through clear instructions, as well as being their to debug issues. This need for collective configuration was also felt to be a place to be in contact with and make sense of automated captioning software.<br><br> If you need to use Live Caption here are steps to run them locally on Chrome. This needs you to download the browser to then join the call.
Live Caption is only available in English. <br>On your computer, download and open Chrome.
<br>At the top right, click menu button and then&nbsp;Settings.
<br>At the bottom of the Settings page, click&nbsp;Accessibility.
<br>Turn on&nbsp;Live Caption. Tips: <br>When you play a video, to turn on captions, at the top right click Media control.
<br>To use Live Captions for videos that auto-play, turn on the video volume.
<br>When you click away from the tab with sound, live captions will appear in a hover-bubble that you can drag. To return to the tab with audio, click. <br><br>Here I share the frictions we found with FLOSS video calls when trying to find accessible platforms and ways of meeting through them.<br><br><br>
<br>This did have a way of doing live captions, but needed you to set it up from the backend and host Jitsi yourself to do this. We both did not host a Jitsi instance, nor could find one that had this already installed.
<br>After the first workshop, we also realized that Jitsi can only host a small group of people, and the workshop size meant people could not always access the session.
<br><br>
<br>This had room for <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="%5Bhttps://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions%5D(https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://configure-able.info/[https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions](https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions)" target="_self">live captioning</a> (which is great!), but for a workshop like this that lacked the funds to hire a live-captioner, there was no automated option.
<br><br>Here is a list of addons for Firefox that were also tested out and did not quite work or were not accessible.<br>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/auto-subtitle/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/auto-subtitle/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/ideas/live-captioning/idi-p/7548" target="_self">https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/ideas/live-captioning/idi-p/7548</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/add-subtitles/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/add-subtitles/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/substital/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/substital/</a>
<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/improvised-captions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Improvised Captions.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:41:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-fra Processing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>This focus group is to reflect on In-grid's collective organisational methods through a framing of critical access. The focus will be accessible to member's reorientation but it will be a time for us to look back and reflect on how we have started to configure our own infrastructure and background away from big tech institutions and towards feminist and intersectional community infrastructures. In this reflection I hope for us to articulate together through processing our inquiry, a few figures (metaphors) of our own to make accessible these situated relations. To do this we will think through how we have found frictions, or inflexibility when working socially and technically. These will form contours for us to reflect on how we have enabled our collaboration to be Configure-able together. This interplay being the place we form figures and narratives of access from, and where we as a collaboration have flexed towards accessible futures and away from institutional inflexibility .<br><br><br>
<br>Go over questions for G
<br>Define together inflexibility and in-flex + qs to help us think through them.
<br>Feel out some topics or experiences to reflect on the inflexibility and then our in-flex-ability.
<br><br><br>What are the systematic and institutional relations that hold/held us in place? From Ahmed - lines holding norms of relations in place. + Aimi Hamraie Flexibile users and soft bodies being conformed to hard machines.<br>
<br>
Systemic issues around CAPITALISM aside. University structure, jobs/working relationships hold some elements in place, and enable certain actions. <br>
Institutions, these come with some privileges but academia/large institutions can be ableist, smaller grass roots organisations that are not driven by the logics of capitalism can enable alt spaces. <br>
How we stay attached to these institutions or stay with the difficulties of systemic issues, but find wiggle room, how we make wiggle room. <br>
All the other things, like race, class, gender etc etc etc <br>
Social and also contractual relationships <br>
Time = money under the jobbing job world. And collectivising means we can pool time or labour in a time-poor world. <br>
The Catch 22 of being able to prioritise art/research/things that matter for early career researchers/artists/makers is that you already have to have done these things to get the jobs/roles where you are given time for that. <br>Post-austerity efficiency<br>
What are the things that disable(d) us from doing what we desire(d) in that relation? <br>
Time, space, funding, prestige, brain space, emotional capacity <br>
Dumb systems that's difficult to work with (Ex: No bank options for non- profitable small collective) <br>Working as a collective, that is not a business or a charity or an institution, makes it difficult to interface with other bodies. Transitioning from a group of individuals to a group that is legally definable? <br>
Right to work, visas etc <br>
wage labour slavery &amp; and chronic health un-diagnosis that both disable/enable my capacity to do anything whether for work or socially, or towrds organising/meeting/ etc <br>What restrains/ed our capacities relationally and materially?<br>
<br>accountability to each other as a group
<br>defining the boundaries of the group. intimacy / maintaining intimacy (is protecting too intense a word), while balancing openness. Project Grant Funding topics (not for this focus group). Maybe we need to be more strict about who we are inviting in and for how long, what the accountabilities etc
<br>expectations from others in terms of availability/ capacity
<br>What does this friction contour?<br>
<br>Wanting to be open but additionally needing some static for contracts and stuff
<br>Too much admin workload on a few people when having more flexible form/ infrastructure
<br><br><br>How do/did we process and feel out that restraint?<br>
<br>Accept what works for the moment and being honest about the solution and the restraint
<br>How did we (want to) flex and wiggle towards our desires?<br>What did we do to enable us to get close to the space/relation possible that we needed?<br>How would we have changed or approached this differently? <br><br><br>These don't have to be mutually exclusive, maybe more starting points?<br><br><br>
<br>Small tech-ing rather than divesting (cloud dependant). Not an issue with the technology more than how that tech is wielded
<br>clumsiness
<br>no one wants to do the boring stuff for free!!!! aka sysadmin / admin / notes
<br>how to make maintenance a joyful and pleasurable space
<br>tinkering with our own structures can be pleasurable
<br>different social relational boundaries / rules systems of collaborating with other groups / institutions can produce anxiety or suck the joy out of the "boring" stuff
<br>relational boundaries are helpful/healthy. sad as it is capitalist logics give a shorthand for boundaries between service providers and collaborators. without going at the speed of trust it's hard to jump into different relational structures. <br>big tech smooths the edges of so we are choosing the bumpy edges<br>
inflexibility:
<br>lack of joy as default for maintenance
<br>easy of use - hidden politics
<br>lack of community
<br>frictionless - no way of being in touch with it.
<br>product
<br>convenience in exchange for bad politics
<br>scales can be overwhelming.<br>
Configure-able In-frastructures
<br>interdependence
<br>affective support as well as functional actions . . .
<br>spreading the load of the "inconvenience" of using smaller grass roots cloud service. making room for inconvenience. making visible the labour of maintaining these services. <br>choosing the scoping of re-clouding. picking collaborators (like servus)
<br><br><br>
<br>sharing and bringing back knowledge is something many of us are invested in but the inflexibility :
<br>takes a lot of labor<br> inflexibility <br>
<br>anxiety + relations + penal <br>lots of work . . <br>no funding support to do it. . . (unpaid)
<br>needs personnel relations to share
<br>mainly people with mainy things going on<br>
Configure-able In-frastructures
<br>tic, repetitions, small scales of repetitive. <br>patience and care
<br>not making assumptions that people know whats going on
<br>being generous with time and knowledge.
<br>clarrity <br>caring about pedagogy
<br>clear refrences <br>vulnerable
<br><br><br> in-flex<br>
<br>Scales of institutional norms
<br>What choices do we have, how to work with resources we can access
<br>Socially relating (differing needs and desires)
<br>how we decide politics and who we align with
<br>capacity for consensus . . . to what extend we delegate decisions or not
<br>CIA's Simple Sabotage Field Manual LOL<br>
Configure-able In-frastructures
<br>Slowing down
<br>love n care n openness
<br>variety in decision making, bespoke decision making, intuition, trust
<br>being okay with being uncomfortable
<br>sedimented trust. <br>let the chaos reign!!!!<br> <br><br><br>
<br>
too flex for insti - but a form that fits our needs <br>
three kids in a long coat pretending to be what they expect. <br><br><br>These are very quickly written sum ups, but hope it helps. Do add or edit if you feel they misrepresent or you have q's or other opinions. . . <br><br><br>(Hamraie, 2017) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6</a>.<br>Writes about the formation of the figure of the user within industrial design and how this was formed from the understanding that human bodies are soft and malleable unlike machines, which are hard, determined and static things humans have to be shaped around. This pulls from a eugenics histories, and also orient ergonomics as a place to shape people as much as it is machines to humans. With critical access here Hamraie questions how we can make room for machines to flex to users instead of this normalising and violent history. <br><br>(Cowan &amp; Rault, 2024) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://punctumbooks.com/titles/heavy-processing/" target="_self">https://punctumbooks.com/titles/heavy-processing/</a><br>Talks about bringing queer practices of heavy processing social relations as a way to re-approach the heavy processing needed to start to imagine ethical, de-colonial and anti-abelist technologies. Thinking with it to how In-grid has our own sorts of processing, ones sedimented through relations of trust, in-stability and care.<br><br>(Maier et al., 2020) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/" target="_self">https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/</a><br>A crip manifesto looking into fractals and repeated patterns as ways to move us beyond the known and into a crip infinite. Here I am highlighting their focus on repetition or a tic we might have, recursively forming actions and relations. . . <br><br>(Sarah Ahmed, 2014) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/" target="_self">https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/</a><br>(Pritchard, 2025) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom" target="_self">https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom</a><br>Here thinking about how to reform roles that are pre-figured or sedimented into relations, whether gender, user, disabled, etc. In these thinking how we can collectively wiggle into these spaces, making capacity for the practices we bring with us and desire to be there as well.<br><br>(Mingus, 2017) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/" target="_self">https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/</a><br>Talking about the need for intimacy in understanding the nuance and care need in access. Here thinking through our expansive intimacies in relation and forming infrastructural access, how we take time, know who might need what, and care for each other to be in that space together. <br><br>(Gearty &amp; Marshall, 2021) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4" target="_self">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4</a><br>This text looks into a reflection on first person action research as a methodology. It looks into how through situated inquiry and one that takes on internal and external arcs of enquiry through both personnel and systemic relations. Here thinking about how we can reflect through these methods to inquire into our own practices internally and externally.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-fra Processing.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-fra-processing/in-fra-processing.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-fra Processing/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-fra-processing/entries/in-fra_processing-working-pad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-fra Processing/entries/In-fra_processing working pad.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:41:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intro In-grid]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>In-grid is a trans*feminist collective of artists/educators/technologists working in and around digital infrastructures. In-grid has been working together since 2019, and is made up of a fluid group of people dispersed globally.<br><br><br>This combined panel takes a critical look at digital "cloud" infrastructures. It explores how collectives and communities counter these centralised models through their situated relations, methods and technical practices. <br>The Combined Panel takes the form of:<br>
<br>A Panel
<br>A workshop &lt;-- We are here
<br>A Hosted Blog &lt;-- We will be posting to here
<br><br><br>For the panel we brought together a range of researchers and practitioners. Each panellist shared their nuanced context and how their collectives*communities are making transformations in infrastructures. We did this to see how system admins and community organisers are forming a diversity of nuanced and situated protocols and ways of collaborating otherwise.<br><br><br>Today's workshop aims to bring together the combined panel's conceptual elements with material socio-technical practice. In this session we will enact the creation of a speculative set of protocols that aim to question the relational complexities of editing, updating and maintaining a collective server, and learning some basic technical skills along the way!<br>The end goal is to have collectively edited set of protocols that we publish to an html page on the server.<br><br><br>The blog element aims to extend conversation from the panel through our own federated infrastructure, subverting and hacking the hierarchies of this conference. It brings this research together in a space that can sit both inside/outside*beyond the conference.<br>Access it at: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ci.servpub.net/about" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://ci.servpub.net/about" target="_self">ci.servpub.net</a><br><br><br>We will also be making and editing a set of protocols as we work through the steps of this workshop. <br>The protocols will be hosted on an html file on the server, and is accessible at this URL page: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html" target="_self">https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html</a><br><br><br>When it comes to making collaborative community driven sociotechnical infrastructure, there is always a complex network of relations that we have to work through. Negotiating every relation when we enter a space could be very complex and time consuming, as we will see, but setting protocols helps us firm up ways of working and relational conventions that ease this flow. Through setting these protocols together we mean to disobey the norms of network infrastructures and actively re-scope how we come to these systems and relations together.<br><br><br><img alt="servpubDiagram2024" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" target="_self"><br><br><br>Lets give a little context of working with computers<br><br><br>So most people are probably used to working through a graphical user interface (GUI), which is a relatively recent way of interfacing with a computer. This is great for accessibility but also tends to scope and direct the abilities and capacities you have on your computer, as in there are only so many buttons or things you can show in a communicable way. <br><br><br><img alt="howdy.png" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/howdyterminal.png" target="_self"><br>Terminal is a more classic way of working with a machine, and roughly speaking is the step between punch-card/magnetic tape style computing and a GUI. It is a very simple but powerful interface that lets you run basically any command on your system through a text interface. Compared to a GUI this space is more "risky" as you can do anything from anywhere, such as deleting the entire hard disc (not advised). It also means that there are no limitations to your system administration so you have access to a granular level of working. <br><br><br>When entering into this more "risky" space on a computer network, it is good to set some intentions and work out how to move through this space with care. As we go though these next steps getting into terminal have a think about what it means to be in this place of power/risk, and what relations you think you need to care for and form protocols for?<br>It can also be a great place to think about if/how your system let's you into this place of power, and what relations this empowering brings with it. <br><br><br>This depends on your platform, so...<br><br><br>On a Mac it is already installed! So all you need to do is:<br>
<br>Search up Terminal
<br>Open it!
<br><br><br>There are similar programs to terminal already installed, but not the same language (bash), so the easiest way to get going is:<br>
<br>Install git Bash from <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/git-for-windows/git/releases/tag/v2.44.0.windows.1" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/git-for-windows/git/releases/tag/v2.44.0.windows.1" target="_self">HERE</a>
<br>Then open it up!
<br><br><br>As we said before terminal is a text/syntax-based way of interfacing your machine and we are going to introduce a few basic commands and concepts to get us going today.<br><br><br>Let's simply use echo to get our terminal to say HI!.<br>To do this use:<br>echo &lt;message&gt;
<br>e.g.<br>echo HI!
<br><br><br>Now lets see who your computer!<br>Show the name of the currently logged in user:<br>whoami
<br>Show the name of the machine is given on the network:<br>hostname
<br><br><br>Much of working on the command line involves navigating around your system without the use of a Graphical User Interface (GUI).<br>However, we will essentially be navigating around normal computer folder hierarchies like below:<br>root/
├─ directoryname/ ├─ anotherdirectory/ ├─ aFileName.txt
<br><br>Directory&nbsp;: also known as a folder<br>Print working directory that you are currently in:<br>pwd
<br>List current directory contents:<br>ls
<br><br><br>Now to move between directories/folders we use cd like so<br>cd &lt;directory_name&gt;
<br>e.g.<br>cd folder1
<br>
We can use a folder that was shown with ls in the last step!<br>
You can also check whats in the new folder with ls to see that you have moved.
<br><br><br>Prompt
In this unfamiliar space how do we keep track of where we are, what we've done &amp; what commands we may need in the future?<br>
...or any other concerns!
<br><br><br>Secure Shell (SSH) is a way of working on another machine from your own, working in their shell (bash). <br>It basically lets you work on another computers terminal remotely. This is the way you will work on most servers or remote/faceless computers (computers without a screen).<br><br><br><img alt="Diagram showing how these devices are connected and communicate over the internet and via the SSH protocol" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/sshdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br>The SSH protocol enables us to talk securely to our server by encrypting and authenticating all of our communication/interfacing through the network. <br>Traditionally tech has a metaphor of SSH as a secure hand shake protocol, but it will be great to think about what metaphor or relation we want when it comes to crossing boundaries and spaces. <br>Do we want to hand shake or do we think . . . would enable . . . <br><br><br>Again this may be a bit different on different systems, as some will have this already installed and some will need to install it. <br>if you are on Mac or Linux you may need to install it with:<br>sudo apt install openssh-client
<br>If you are on gitbash on windows, it should be installed.<br><br><br>To SSH into the pi we need to know what the IP address of the pi is. <br>An IP address is basically the postcode/address we will find the pi at on the network.<br>To do this on the pi we write:<br>hostname -I
<br>This will print out something like 192.168.0.8, and we need to save this to SSH into the pi<br><br><br>Now that we have the IP address, any computer on that network can request to SSH into the Pi through these commands:<br>ssh &lt;user_name&gt;@&lt;ip&gt;
<br>eg.<br>ssh ci@192.168.8.120
<br>You are now "logging into" the pi, so it will ask for the password here and that is . . . . . . <br><br><br>You should now see your terminal username change from your laptop's local user to something like: <br>ci@servpub~$.
<br>If you want to exit out of the pi (we don't atm) type:<br>exit
<br>Hit enter. You will need to have exited the pi before setting up your ssh key. <br><br><br>We won't do it here as it takes a minute too long, but to do this securely we would set up a set of keys which, one private and one public, that will do the "hand shake" instead of a less secure password. <br><br><br>Prompt
How do we navigate another machine through our own "interface"?<br>
What are the relational agreements to being on this other machine?
<br><br><br>Caring for a server includes routine tasks like updating/upgrading the system software, tiding up files, creating new users &amp; giving access permissions, paying attention to errors and bug reports.<br>Sharing a server space presents the added complexity of doing all of the above with consideration other collectives' and/or groups' pre-existing protocols (eg. Systerserver)<br><br><img alt="Diagram showing all of the connections within the Servpub Infrastructure. It shares how devices are connected through a VPN and server to host things online." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/connectionsdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br><br>Sudo enables us to take on a superuser role.<br>
This means that we have all the security permissions for that system. This is a "very risky" role, as here you can do anything on the server/computer. With sudo you can actually delete the entire system or make other similar drastic commands, but it also means that we have the ability to manage and configure our system to our needs.<br>When we come to writing protocols for sudo, what does it mean for us to be a "superuser" or an admin, and what care and consideration should we take on in these protocols?<br><br><img alt="Diagram shares how different users can connect to systems with different permissions and access levels." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/usersdiagram.jpg" target="_self"><br><br><br>To become sudo you just need to:<br>sudo su
<br>And then enter the password when prompted.<br><br><br>Prompt
Super User can Do! a lot... what permissions are we comfortable navigating?<br>
How intimate are we with our machines?
<br><br><br>Tmux is what is called a multiplexer, which is a software that lets us collectively work one terminal session. <br>This is how many collectives and collaborative networks work together on servers in one space. It lets us edit and run commands in one space and take responsibility and practice our infra becoming together.<br>When we come to writing protocols we might want to think about what it means to be one user together, and how can we keep everyone at the same pace and comfortable levels of understanding. <br><br><br>Now we are all sudo we can initiate a shared session to work in together.<br>To do this we use:<br>tmux new -s hugs
<br>Now we need to name our collective space. If we think back*forward in this workshop, what are the intentions, dynamics and relations we want to collectively name this space with?<br><br><br>Now we have an active session we can join it by just typing:<br>tmux a -t hugs
<br>
Rember we have to be sudo to join this!
<br><br><br>Now we can say hi to one another and say cute messages in the space by:<br>echo &lt;message&gt;
<br>Say something to welcome each other into this session, you may need to take turns.<br><br><br>As we saw even each of us writing an echo command takes a little bit of choreographing. When this gets more complicated, like writing complex configuration files, you can imagine it gets even more tricky.<br>So here we need to think about how we might manage collective editing. What operational metaphor might we use to describe the relationship between the person typing and the others? Who and how do we choose to type? How do we take care of every voice in that conversation?<br><br><br>We've created a simple html document to edit. We need to navigate to that file, open and edit it. <br>First lets navigate to the folder its inside and list its contents.<br>cd /var/www/pubdoc
ls
<br>We should see a file called:<br>ci_protocols.html<br><br><br>Now we are in the right folder we can edit the file with nano which is a terminal base text editor. <br>To open the file with nano we do:<br>nano ci_protocols.html
<br>This will open the file in the terminal.<br><br><br><img alt="A screenshot capturing a bright pink terminal interface which has the HTML page we are editing shown in nano. Nano is a basic text editor based in the terminal." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/nanoofhtml.png" target="_self"><br>Tip
Being terminal you have to navigate with the keyboard, and also copy and past by right clicking (not "CNTRL+C/P")
<br><br><br>From here we can then add text and images using basic HTML syntax.<br>So for now add a message or paste in some ascii art with the help of these links:<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" target="_self">ascii text gen</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" target="_self">ascii image gen</a><br><br><br>Now if we return to the file online at:<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html" target="_self">https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html</a><br>we will see our beautiful inputs.<br><br><br><br><br>When we finish up working together there are lots of things we can do to make it easier to return to our work, make it legible to others, as well as caring for the infrastructure we're working in. This could include careful documentation, understanding how to save and record edits, and exiting programs in their nuanced ways.<br><br><br>We've finished working together and now we would like to leave our TMUX session. This is a little more complex than it might appear. Leaving a session using an 'exit' command will delete the session for others, and you will lose the record of your edits together. Instead we can either:<br>Close the entire terminal session window, or use Ctrl-b. This will retain the terminal session for you to use again in the future. <br><br><br>Let's consider collectively how to ensure we exit safely, using a door rather than an ejector seat. How does this action differ from exiting other softwares and how does this attention affect our relationships.<br><br><br>prompt
How do we negotiate the space of working collectively as one user?<br>
What other considerations need to be voiced?
<br><br><br>Now we have all the protocols ready lets add them to the HTML file with nano again.<br>Once we have edited the HTML, we can launch our page in a browser! <br>At <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html" target="_self">https://servpub.net/ci_protocols.html</a> <br><br><br>Practising infrastructuring collectively can be (intentionally) a slow, careful and unscalable process, so it's important to acknowledge our incremental changes, achievements and presence. <br><br><br><br><br>Our (ongoing) documentation <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/In-grid-collective/servPubWiki.git" target="_self">https://github.com/In-grid-collective/servPubWiki.git</a><br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Collective Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/collective-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Collective Infrastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/entries/practicing-protocols.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Collective Infrastructures/entries/Practicing Protocols.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:41:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/servpubdiagram2024.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents" target="_self">Docs:00 Contents - wiki4print</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>
<a href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" class="is-unresolved"> </a><img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self">
<br><br><img alt="A diagram of the Servpub network infrastructure made by In-grid." src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/raw/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" target="_self"><br>A diagram of the Servpub network infrastructure made by In-grid.<br><br>These docs offer up and share the processes and technical practices that made up the back-end of the Servpub network infrastructure. These docs aim to act not only as a resource to share how to take up and hack these VPN infrastructures for yourself, but also to present alongside this the practices, networks and histories that have emerged into the Servpub server infrastructures.<br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01_Setup_a_Local_Collaborative_Environment" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:01 Setup a Local Collaborative Environment" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01_Setup_a_Local_Collaborative_Environment" target="_self">01 Setup a Local Collaborative Environment</a> <br>Learn how to set up a computer locally and how to make users, collectively connect and care for it. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:02_Local_Server_Setup_with_Nginx" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:02 Local Server Setup with Nginx" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:02_Local_Server_Setup_with_Nginx" target="_self">02 Local Server Setup with Nginx</a> <br>Learn how to set up the computer as a server on your local network and host a basic HTML page! <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:03_VPN_with_Tinc" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:03 VPN with Tinc" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:03_VPN_with_Tinc" target="_self">03 VPN with Tinc</a> <br>Learn how to set up a Virtual Private Network (VPN) with Tinc so that you can have a portable server. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:04_Reverse_Proxy_with_NginX" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:04 Reverse Proxy with NginX" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:04_Reverse_Proxy_with_NginX" target="_self">04 Reverse Proxy with NginX</a> <br>Learn how to pass public internet traffic through the VPN to a site on the portable server. <br><br>If you would like to follow along in real life (IRL), you will need these bits of hardware!<br>
<br>Small board computer (SBC) <br>We used a raspberry pi, although You don’t necessarily need to use a pi to create a collaborative environment, you could use another type of computer. To understand more about why we chose to use a pi, you can find our notes here <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Chapter_2a:_Server_Issues:_Platform_Infrastructure" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Chapter 2a: Server Issues: Platform Infrastructure" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Chapter_2a:_Server_Issues:_Platform_Infrastructure" target="_self">Chapter 2a: Server Issues: Platform Infrastructure</a> <br>Peripherals <br>HDMI, screen, keyboard, mouse etc. <br>A laptop or other personal computer <br>It would be good to have SSH installed on your laptop. Most OS have it by default now, if not then manually install following the steps under <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01.3_SSH" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:01.3 SSH" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01.3_SSH" target="_self">01.3 SSH</a> <br>Knowledge of terminal/bash <br>For an intro to basic terminal/bash commands see <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" target="_self">00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet</a> <br>A Server with public IP (optional) <br>This is to hos a VPN on, but is only needed if you want to host things publically. <br><br>If you're new to sever-ing and sysadmin, you may find the following guides useful as they explain more of the basics of how these things work:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.1_Network_terminology" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:00.1 Network terminology" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.1_Network_terminology" target="_self">00.1 Network terminology</a> <br>Gives an overview of terms we will be using throughout this guide in relation to networking <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" target="_self">00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet</a> <br>Is an introduction to working on the command line. <br><br>In-grid has tried to make these docs accessible and legible (as possible) to both technical and non-technical reading. We have done this through not only try to follow the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.wcag.com/resource/wcag-quick-tips-for-content-writers/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.wcag.com/resource/wcag-quick-tips-for-content-writers/" target="_self">Web Content Access Guidelines</a> but also working with the concept of semi-plain language that Kelsie Acton notes in here chapter Plain Language for Disability Culture in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://nyupress.org/9781479819362/crip-authorship/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://nyupress.org/9781479819362/crip-authorship/" target="_self">Crip Authorship</a>. Acton states this as:<br>
Note on writing: This chapter is written in what I call a semi- plain language style. This means I do the following: <br>Use an active voice
<br>Mostly use the 6000 most common words in the English language
<br>Use short sentences
<br>Use 14 point font
<br>Use “I” and “you” <br>Following Acton, In-grid understands this as not trying to assimilate dialogues into dominant technical talking points, but we approach this practice through critical access to distribute and share the expertise of systems and make the disputable from many backgrounds and knowledges.<br>In-grid also approaches this as a place of design friction. This is where we have made room within and around these hard network infrastructures with and for our softer practices of collective access. In this space of semi-plain In-grid have iterated our own attempt at semi-plain technical docs!<br>We may also use "us" and "we" to state In-grid and Servpub collaborators who made this infrastructure.<br>If you want a light, but still deep exploration of the setup, check out the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self">Index of each section</a> listed above.<br>If you have any access requests, please email: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:in-grid@in-grid.io" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://configure-able.info/mailto:in-grid@in-grid.io" target="_self">in-grid@in-grid.io</a><br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Docs.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/in-docs.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Docs/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/entries/docs00-contents-wiki4print.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/entries/Docs00 Contents - wiki4print.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:40:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Practising Protocols X Femfester Workshop Pad]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>In the workshop to write the Femfester, In-grid members came together in person and online, ate some nice food and tasty snacks, caught up, but also set up their new server with Servus, and along the way (con)figured out what relations and politics we wanted to bring there and how!<br><br>These are the prompts we made alongside setting up our VPS server with our members. Each step we reflect, re-imagine, and re(con)figure out what we desire each relation, space and dynamic to be for us together. These were done to enable us to find our collective orientation whilst orienting our infrastructures. These are all notes of much deeper and complex conversations, but try to map and inform where we are at.<br><br><br>Here was a pre-figuring out of what we desired our coding relations to be.<br>
<br>
Doing things in pairs / groups <br>
Making sure everyone is on the same page before starting work <br>
Documentation *so choices can be rolled back/remade if necessary <br>
Be soft with sudo <br>
Working slowly, doing things in steps, not rushing through, stopping at a step rather than getting half way through something. <br>
double check what you are about to do before doing it, as may be irreversible * Talk <br>
Consider institutional implications for managed machines <br>
Keep everyone up to date. <br><br><br>Here we logged into the server through <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" target="_self">SSH</a> and questioned the metaphor and figure it brings of a handshake. <br>
<br>When creating metaphors mention what is being replaced
<br><br><br>Here we approached the "sudo" command (means super user do), which enables admin rights on a system and for you to undertake maintenance. Here we imagined how we desired to configure these processes and rights.<br>When sudo we should take extra care to make sure what we are doing is wanted by all. Work in pairs (if you can)? For any major changes at least... <br>Should we be anonyms sudo? Or su user to track<br>Should sudo be used alone? <br><br><br>Here we set up the users for the server, but also took time to manifest the figures we imagined being on this server. Here questioning the norms of user/server and individualized relations and how we want to enact them together otherwise.<br>Not users but:<br>maintainers?<br>carers?<br>Member?<br>Players?<br>Collaborators and caretakers<br>it is nice to be individuals in a collective<br>characters<br>Conversationalists<br>persona<br>Infra as another collaborator not users/using<br>Fistulas <br><br><br>Here we uploaded SSH keys for those accounts and then closed password access to the server. This in norms makes the server "sercure", we took up this to imagine what safety means for us instead of security.<br>Is transparency safety? No single point of failure/hidden information or is it helpful not to be able to delete something.<br>Understanding the risks and making decisions based on understanding<br>Not having knowledge lie with one person<br>Everyone should have ability to access knowledge<br>Don't make ring-fence around particular roles<br>How do we make people feel unafraid of making changes<br>But at the same time aware of what the "risks" are<br>Is it more about learning how to move with caution and care<br>The idea is not to move fast / gung-ho / "trigger happy", <br>but rather checking and double checking before doing<br>How can we do things like check a process before doing something, I'm thinking of Nginx command to check if the config file is valid before restarting the server... can we try to research that for all software we use? If we end up making our own tools, can we build caution / testing / care into our procedures, so that people feel confident that the changes they are about to make are safe to do? <br>Demystifying what is safe protocols etc. <br>Boundaries are helpful between the server and outside the server<br><br><br>Here we logged into TMUX an SSH multiplexer (basically a way to collaborate on server work). We wanted to imagine what collaborative relations we desired, but got caught up on TMUX technicalities. . . <br>
<br>
Turns out that typing exit in a string seems to exit it also <br>
Nominate who will type, and check in when people are getting tired. <br>Take turns, maybe signal end of a string/phrase? Over, fin, out! fnx your turn bbz<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/entries/workshop-pad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/entries/Workshop Pad.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:37:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Femfester]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>This Femfester is In-grid’s iteration of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" target="_self">feminist server manifesto</a>. As we rub up against and dance our way into network practices, a festering acts as a place to form intentions and imagine how we want to collectively meet here. We fester as we care for the holes in our pipelines, tend to the ooze that undulates out and sit with these leaky seamful infrastructures. We don't aim to cure these frictions or plug these holes, but to care for them. We ask how we can enable infrastructuring to fester otherwise from our pulsating practices?<br><br> A femfestering Server . . . . . - Is a situated technology. The server feels out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices. - Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing and maintaining a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affair. - Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relations of the bodies gathered around them. - Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. - Does not strive for seamlessness, as it creates a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible and inaccessible. - Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages we need to abolish. - Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice. - Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. - Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; practices queering client-server relations where they can. - Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. - Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible. - Does not confuse safety with security. - Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity. - Tries hard not to apologies when they are not available, as they learn to communicate their capacities. <br><br><br>We started writing our manifesto by returning to the original Feminist Server Manifesto, and reading it line by line together, each member taking it in turns, but also doing this no deterministically and one taking after where the other left off. We also chatted about our relations to it and how it had influenced us in our work and lives. <br><br><br>Here we then took space to do a sedimented In-grid practice of free writing to enable all members to anonymously (+ without anxiety) and collectively form our own lines for a manifesto.<br>New things: <br>Balance between caution/testing/care and empowerment
<br>Does not police language, but reads intentions and actions<br>Form different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.<br>Enable us to practice and perform new relations of radical politics that we need now!<br>Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurity<br>Rotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound.<br>Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.<br>Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time.<br>Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicit<br>Not geolocated but bounded/held in a community<br>Not 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support us<br>Consciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processes<br>Balance between caution/testing/care and empowerment<br>Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". <br>Does not police language, but reads intentions and actions<br>Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate <br>Transparent about power and how it's being used<br>Notes:<br>
<br>
Opens herself to expose processes, tools, sources, habits, patterns (Katie was talking about this as transparency / accessibility) <br>
Does not strive for seamlessness. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible (what is the relationship between seamlessness and transparency) <br>Seamlessness require a lot of labour and obscure the effort behind the scenes.<br>By making knowledge of a system or the system itself accessible, we don't need to make the system seamless? <br>What is the difference between accessibility and transparency? <br>Accessibility of sudo<br><br><br>We then took the original server manifesto's lines and started to align our own with them, figuring out how we oriented in different ways.<br>A Festering Server is . . . . . a 10 minute manifesto<br>
Is a situated technology. They feel out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices <br>our lines:<br>
<br>feeling out what we (both us and the server) need and want from this relation.
<br>Not geolocated but bounded/held in a community
<br>
Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affaire. <br> our lines:<br>
<br>Consciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processes
<br>
Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time. <br>care for the ooze of infrastructure, and find pleasure in the frictions.
<br>
Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relation of the bodies gathered around it <br>our lines:<br>
<br>Composting/rusting/festering, materially bound.
<br>
Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. <br>our lines:<br>
<br>Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". <br>Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicit
<br>Form different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.
<br>Transparent about power and how it's being used
<br>
Does not strive for seamlessness, as it is a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible <br>our lines: <br>
<br>Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate <br>Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurity
<br>
Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages to abolish. <br>our lines:<br>
<br>Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.
<br>Not 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support us
<br>Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". <br>
Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice <br>our lines:<br>
<br>Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate <br>Rotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound.
<br>
Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. <br>
Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; and practices queerying client-server relations where they can <br>
Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. <br>
Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible <br>
Does not confuse safety with security <br>
Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity <br>
Tries hard not to apologize when they are sometimes not available, but <br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/entries/femfester-manifesto.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/entries/Femfester Manifesto.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:36:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Glossary]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This Glossary shares some of the key terms and words used to shape this research. These descriptions aim to accessibly offer up how this research works with crip and queer feminist theory to form critical access informed approaches to community infrastructuring. These terms help to understand how this research makes sense of the many bodies, technologies and relations that it is in touch with. The glossary is not complete or totalizing; rather, it traces words and concepts I have oriented with to bring together, move through, and make friction with the unknowable and unpredictable actions of community infrastructuring. <br>The references for these terms can be found on the repo's <a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/About/References.md" href="https://configure-able.info/about/references.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">References</a> page.<br><br><br>Misfitting is a situated methodology of caring for how people and their communities want to be oriented politically and materially, and attending to how these desires misfit within the determinate slots of institutions and infrastructures. Misfitting as a method makes space for bodies to (dis)orient infrastructures, relations and politics through their ambivalent relationships and embodied expertise to these systems. As a situated process, misfitting animates systems from their localities and shapes complex systems and knowing from emergent actions instead of set plans.<br>(Garland-Thomson 2011)<br>(Rice et al. 2024)<br><br><br>Friction is a process of access making. Friction arises both from the feeling of misfitting, and the ways that crip and queer bodies make sense of what barriers exist, as well as making access through friction, making disorienting requests, improvising infrastructures and transforming these feelings into change. In crip theory, friction rubs up against itself through wordplay; there can be pain from frictions, but there is also a possibility for pleasure and joy, which is often never imagined. Friction in this research is a place of joyous, pleasurable and embodied access making in action that also makes room for and validates its awkward and painful processes.<br>(Kafer 2013)<br>(Hamraie and Fritsch 2019)<br>(Hamraie 2023)<br><br><br>Wiggle room emerges from friction making around the categories and relations that people are prescribed by the norms of systems. People and communities make wiggle room together by feeling out how these determined categories and relations misfit the bodyminds they enclose and creating space through friction for relations that affirm their lives and desired orientations.<br>(Ahmed 2014)<br>(Pritchard 2022)<br><br><br>The Table is a metaphor for the institutional norms that have been gradually sedimented into determined and inflexible relations. Tables in this research take many forms, from my desk, to excell tables, to kitchen tables, to interview tables, and to operating tables. This research asks how these tables and their sedimented norms put limits on how we can be together in relation. In theory and practice, this thesis considers how we can start to wiggle room to disorient these tables to affirm our lives, community relations, practices and politics.<br>(Ahmed 2006)<br>(Suchman 2012)<br><br><br>The Crip Table imagines what a table shaped by crip politics and community might feel like. The crip table makes room to imagine how systems, infrastructures and their inflexible relations can be flexible to and shaped by the bodyminds they misfit and cause friction with towards indeterminate relations of life affirmation, community desire, and justice.<br>(Mingus 2017)<br>(Kafai 2021)<br>(Kafer 2023)<br>(Simms and Marangoni 2025)<br><br><br>The Bodily Horizon situates how bodies are in relation with the things around them. The Bodily Horizon makes room to question what is within reach, what can be changed, and what limits and capacities there are within the actions we take. It makes sense of the frictions of the present while also questioning how bodies desire to be oriented towards futures, and what they desire to be within reach. The Bodily Horizon comes from a body in motion, one that feels and makes change between the present and the future.<br>(Ahmed 2006)<br><br><br>In crip theory, the Bodymind is the refusal of the split between mind and body made within Western medicine and philosophy. The bodymind is a place of feeling, sense- and knowledge-making. In breaking down boundaries between mind and body, this research is also intimate with the boundaries between bodies and the relations that impact or misfit them. By questioning the determined ways bodies, minds and their matters are separated, this research considers how relations can be transformed through entangled and distributed sense-making and expertise.<br>(Clare 2017)<br>(Schalk 2018)<br><br><br>This research makes-sense through embodied practices that are situated within the social, relational and emotional context of the those bodyminds misfitting within configurations. By making-sense in this research I bring in the backgrounded knowledges and expertise of systems that offer up a plurality of narratives, perspectives and practices that can disorient the normalized and isolated plans of systems. In this approach I work with creative, discursive and textural inquiries that shape systems through the processes and practices that are accessible and make-sense to those manifesting them.<br>(Marshall 1999)<br>(Marshall 2004)<br>(Gearty and Marshall 2021)<br>(Pritchard et al. 2021)]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/glossary.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Glossary.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:29:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disobedient Action Research Methods]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>The indeterminate diagram above represents this project's disobedient methodology as it aims to (dis)orient the standardized and prescribed methods of configuration. Each time you visit this page, and every time you click on the diagram, it creates a different composition of actions, sense makings and wiggling of room that this disobedient crip methodology entices. Visually it forms loops and cycles of the icons and terms of this research connected into indeterminate compositions. Each iteration has a generated Alt-text containing the syntax for the diagram, and which can be interpreted in a similarly playful way. The Alt-text is attached to the &lt;div&gt; with the .mermaid class.<br>This code is an edit of another work/performance called <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" target="_self">Pad2Party</a> that Sunni Liao, Yewen Jin and I made as part or <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" target="_self">RealBodies 2.1</a> with In-grid collective.<br><br><br>For this project I have taken on a Disobedient Action Research Methodology. As the above texture and indeterminate diagram tries to highlight, this methodology disobediently refuses to be generalized or normalized into set operations. Instead this project's Trans*methods make wiggle room for bodyminds to access, be in touch with and shape the sociotechnical infrastructures and matters they are impacted by and misfit within. <br>To build up my projects Disobedient Action Research methodology I work with the debugging methods of TiTIPi (Pritchard et al., 2021) and build it up with misfitting methods of Carla Rice et al. (2024) to ask what room can collective embodied inquiries make within infrastructuring. With this methodology I make room to be intimate with and build up collective expertise that question what affirmative infrastructures, practices and relations are within reach socially and technically through independent action. Through this disobedient methodology I re-frame what actions can be taken within academic research, moving to make-sense of what lives are livable beyond assimilation norms of access, organization and infrastructures on institutional terms.<br>Through my Trans*methodology my research is shaped through collective practices, debugging, terminal consoles, bank interfaces, parties, workshops, messaging stickers, VPN's and soft cushions. Coalescing together these many surfaces, textures and tables of research collaborators and I made sense of how our technical practices could be shaped by our backgrounds, expertise and feelings. Through this methodology collectively figuring out what our affirmative community infrastructures are through unfolding actions of access making.<br><br><br>These protocols offer up some of the ways my disobedient methods have unfolded within this research project. These protocols themselves are loose mappings of what happened in this research and offers up how these methods are improvisable, situated, and shaped by their actions.<br><br><br>Practicing Protocols shares how these methods unfolded into a set of accessible workshops that questioned the configurations of network infrastructures. These workshops made wiggle room for people to make sense of and shape network infrastructures through their embodied expertise and situated practices. <br>This protocol unfolded from the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Collective Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/collective-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Collective Infrastructures</a> combined panel, and at the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid</a> workshop. These workshop inquiries made wiggle room for us to unfold collective expertise around our misfitting within the normalized network configurations we have inherited. From misfitting moving to form counter figures, relations and imaginaries for the affirming network infrastructures we desire now.<br><br>This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol took action. It moves from accessible technical documentation that helped us make sense of our embodied misfitting within these configurations. From this misfitting forming our own situated figures and terms for how we want to practice this infrastructure locally.<br><br><br>Improvising Floss Protocols shares how these methods unfolded around making access within FLOSS technologies throughout this research. This protocol offers up how collaborators and I wiggled room between the misfitting of FLOSS and our access knowledges to improvise our own access technologies. Through these practices of access making, making sense of the limits and capacities of access within FLOSS.<br>This protocol unfolded from the the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop</a> I organised with NEoN digital, making the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-ish.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/cozy-ish.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-ish</a> and <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy Night and Day.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/cozy-night-and-day.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy Night and Day</a> themes, as well as manifesting the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-Intentions.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Intentions</a> and <a class="internal-link" data-href="Serving Cozy.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/serving-cozy.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving Cozy install</a>. This protocol unfolded from the wiggled room made within FLOSS technologies for them to be shaped by and affirm our access knowledges, practices and desires.<br><br> This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol made sense of how FLOSS technologies we had in reach misfitted with the access knowledges and practices of the group. From this misfitting moving to wiggle room, improvise and shape the imaginaries and capacities of FLOSS through collective practices of access making.<br><br><br>(Dis)orienting Protocols shares how these methods unfolded when being in touch with and disobediently trying to shape institutional configurations and organization processes. This protocol offers up how collaborators and I made wiggle room around inflexible institutional norms to (dis)orient them towards our backgrounds, politics and desires for the future. <br>This protocol unfolded from collaborating on In-grid's organizational practices that are shared in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="In-fra Processing.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-fra-processing/in-fra-processing.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-fra Processing</a> entry. The protocol was also shaped by the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Disobedient Access Requests.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/disobedient-access-requests.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Disobedient Access Requests</a> that I made towards the Tate's configurations and within <a class="internal-link" data-href="En-crip-ing Time.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/en-crip-ing-time.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">En-crip-ing Time's</a> refusal of the configurations of network time and intimacies.<br><br>This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol (dis)oriented configurations by making wiggle room to feel out our frictions with the sedimented norms of institutions and their organization. From this wiggle room starting to unfold and form our own organizational practices, desires and imaginaries for how we want to orient and improvise them locally. ]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/methods_lcl.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Methods_lcl.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:00:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Practice]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This page shares the practice, inquiries and research this project took towards manifesting Configure-able Infrastructures. These different tables of inquiry emerge through my Disobedient Action Research Methods. These practice based inquiries aim to offer up how this disobedient methodology was shaped by and made room for the indeterminate communities, contexts and relations it was in touch with.<br>These collaborative inquiries are split into the three sections below which each offer up a context, collaboration and unfolding infrastructure that were formed through workshops, focus groups, technical docs, speculative infrastructures and * * * * *.<br><br><br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates an institution wiggling and all of its straight supports at angles to their normalized orientation" src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/configure-able.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries offer up how critical access making and its resulting knowledges offers up Wiggle Room within the misfitting of prescribed configurations. Within the frictious wiggle room of access making, (dis)orienting, hacking and improvising infrastructures through the embodied expertise of the bodies they impact.<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Read more</a><br><br><br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a server grounded through a heart, bringing these often hard systems in touch with soft feelings" src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/in-configure.svg" target="_self"> These inquiries offer up how critical access can be brought into collaborations within non-disabled communities, not as extra time, but as a way to disobediently Wiggle Room within infrastructuring and organization. In this approach, making accessible collective practices through interdependent sense-making and direct actions.<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Read more</a><br><br><br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a cloud with a small grin and a big cozy cup of a hot drink of your choice" src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/cozy.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries offer up how the Cozy-Cloud made Wiggle Room to crip server and network infrastructures through unfolding practices of access making and life affirmation. Through these inquiries and practices questioning how embodied expertise, pleasurable access making and intimacy.<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Read more</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/practice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Practice.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:22:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/configure-able.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/configure-able.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[About]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Configure-Able Infrastructures is the PhD research of George Simms and was undertaken at the University of Plymouth as part of I-DAT, and funded through the doctoral teaching assistant (DTA) program.<br>It is a Joy to share this research, practice and methods with you! I hope they are improvisable and informative when making sense of what affirming infrastructures are for your communities.<br><br><br>This research was brought together through trans-methodological collaborations with members of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.in-grid.io/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.in-grid.io/" target="_self">In-grid collective</a>, the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://cozy-cloud.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cozy-cloud.net/" target="_self">Cozy-Cloud</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://neondigitalarts.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://neondigitalarts.com/" target="_self">NEoN Digital</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://meltionary.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://meltionary.com/" target="_self">M.E.L.T.</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://core.servus.at/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://core.servus.at/" target="_self">Servus.at</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://servpub.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://servpub.net/" target="_self">Servpub</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://cc.practices.tools/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cc.practices.tools/" target="_self">Creative Crowds</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://systerserver.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://systerserver.net/" target="_self">SysterServer</a> and the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://criticalmedialab.ch/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://criticalmedialab.ch/" target="_self">Critical Media Lab</a>. Through these generous collaborations this research had room to be in touch with, shaped by and mutually construct the infrastructures and socialities that manifested it. In this colophon, I make room to thank all of those mentioned above for their contributions to this research.<br><br><br>A selection of the references that have informed and inspired this research and methodology.]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/about.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/About.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:20:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-Grid's In-frastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a server grounded through a heart, bringing these often hard systems in touch with soft feelings" src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg" target="_self"><br>These inquiries offer up how critical access can be brought into collaborations within non-disabled centered communities, not as extra time, but as a way to Wiggle Room within infrastructuring practices for interdependent sense making and collective action. These inquiries take on the form of focus groups, accessible docs and a set of workshops called Practising Protocols that ran both In-ternally with In-grid members as well as publicly at 4S/EASST.<br>These inquiries aim to share how critical access practices and methods make room for a collective like In-grid to question our organizational and network infrastructures by both coming into contact with them, but also by shaping them from our backgrounds and expertise. In this inquiry, especially bring focus to how critical access practices made room for our misfitting within normalizing configurations to unfold into counter expertise and knowledges. With this approach making-sense of the assimilationist norms and politics of network and organizational configuration in a way that where we could refuse, improvise and deviate from the norms we felt friction with.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares a collective focus group with In-grid members to reflect on their organizational practices and approaches. In this session, questioning how misfit within and made friction around the social and institutional inflexibilities our collective were impacted by when trying to organize together.<br><br><br>This entry reflects on a collective inquiry with In-grid members around how we practice and imagine our technical Docs and network infrastructures when informed by critical access making. In these collective practices questioning how prescribed technical configurations and their isolated expertise can be disputed, improvised and refused when made accessible to other backgrounds, capacities and knowledges.<br><br><br>This entry shares a combined panel and workshop organized by In-grid members for 4S/EASST 2024. With this panel element bringing together community practitioners to share their practices of collective infrastructuring. Alongside this we ran the Practicing Protocols workshop which made room for participants to make-sense of and counter the configurations they encountered, misfit within and found friction with during a practical session.<br><br><br>This entry shares a collective workshop where In-grid members came together to run the Practicing Protocols workshop in-ternally. For this iteration we set up our first collective server as well as our first server manifesto called the Femfester. In this workshop, accessibly making-sense of our collective misfitting within the inherited configurations of network infrastructures as a way to manifest them otherwise.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Grid's In-frastructures.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:19:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving In-grid]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This second iteration of the Practising Protocols workshop was run in-ternally with In-grid members. In this session we set up our Virtual Private Server (VPS) that is hosted with Servus. This aims to be an experimental server for us to test and make sense of our network infrastructuring practices. In the workshop we made room to figure out how we wanted to imagine and enact our infrastructure as we configured it. In this process both aiming to make the VPS and its technical practices accessible to members of In-grid, but in doing so making room to (dis)orient and care for the misfitting of these technical practices by bringing them in touch with our collective background and embodied expertise.<br>From this workshop, In-grid manifested our experimental VPS to be encoded through our own counter figures. These ranged from refusing the role of Users to instead be carers, maintainers, players, personas and collaborators. It also made room for us to come into contact with and make sense of the many layers of network security these technologies are kept "safe" through. In response to this sense-making of misfitting forming our own dialogues around how we imagine networks becoming safe through trust, care and intimacy. From manifesting our configure-able VPS infrastructure, we also turned to form our own manifesto for it, called the Femfester (In-grid et al., 2024), and which was published with Servus in the first edition of their <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://publications.servus.at/2024-Artists-Running-Data-Centers/ArtistsRunningDataCenters-servus-at_2024.pdf" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://publications.servus.at/2024-Artists-Running-Data-Centers/ArtistsRunningDataCenters-servus-at_2024.pdf" target="_self">Artists Running Datacentres</a> journal.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the guide for the technical processes undertaken in the workshop. Theses are a few fairly accessible steps with ample Wiggle Room made around them to make-sense of our misfitting within them, and to imagine them otherwise.<br><br><br>This entry shares the collective notes from a shared pad used during the workshop. This shares peoples different thoughts from and inputs to the workshop.<br><br><br>This entry shares the notes from collectively writing the Femfester server manifesto. These were written by In-grid members both in person at the end of the workshop and asynchronously online for the week following it.<br><br><img alt="The images is the icon of the workshop and is a kaomoji (a face made out of letters), which depicts a person with their hand in the air tilted down, symbolising serving" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png" target="_self"><br>
The images is the icon of the workshop and is a kaomoji (a face made out of ASCI letters), which depicts a person with their hand in the air tilted down, symbolizing serving.<br><br><img alt="An image take from the workshop shows members of In-grid in person. We are sat comfortably on a sofa and some chairs in a kitchen/living room, with our backs to the camera." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day-2.jpg" target="_self"><br>
An image take from the workshop shows members of In-grid in person. We are sat comfortably on a sofa and some chairs in a kitchen/living room, with our backs to the camera.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:17:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-fra Processing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This entry shares a focus group run collaboratively with In-grid members, making room for us to reflect on our collective organizational practices, inquiring into how we collectively misfit within systemic inflexibilities. In this focus group, In-grid collectively making-sense of and imagining how we want to negotiate and counter the systemic inflexibilities and limitations we felt when making interdependent actions.<br>This focus group was run online with six members of In-grid, and made room to question a range of issues including our banking/finances, our network infrastructures, collective politics and organization. From these reflections, it made room for us to bring into focus how In-grid orients our collective politics and organization through trust and interdependence, instead of through security politics and their invasive politics of capture. From these norms of security politics and so-called transparency within organization and networks. In-grid worked with critical access making to question how we wanted to bring members in touch with these systemic inflexibilities, frictions and misfittings to make room to form imaginaries and expertise that can improvise, hack and (dis)orient these relations collectively.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the working pad for the focus group with In-grid members. Here you can read into their thoughts and make your own analysis of In-grid's in-frastructural processing.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-fra-processing/in-fra-processing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-fra Processing/In-fra Processing.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:16:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Collective Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This was a combined panel run by In-grid members at 4S/EASST 2024 in Amsterdam. For this, we brought together a panel of different collectives and communities who are actively practicing and re-imagining what their collective infrastructures are through situated practice and direct action. This included members of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://titipi.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/" target="_self">TITiPI</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://neondigitalarts.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://neondigitalarts.com/" target="_self">NEoN Digital</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://julianueno.xyz/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://julianueno.xyz/" target="_self">Júlia Nueno Guitart</a>, and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://shape.au.dk/en/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://shape.au.dk/en/" target="_self">SHAPE</a>. Alongside the panel In-grid members also ran the first iteration of the Practicing Protocols workshop which made room for collaborators to get in touch with network infrastructure, and to make-sense of their configurations, protocols and relations from their embodied expertise and background knowledges.<br>This combined panel and workshop offered up the many ways that collective practices and contexts manifest and situate infrastructural practice with and for different politics, expertise and capacities. In this approach, aiming to share how infrastructures are shaped by the communities, backgrounds and desires that manifest them. With the workshop especially bringing focus to the ways this can be done within technical practices by making room for peoples backgrounds and embodied expertise to come into contact with and shape how these infrastructures are encoded and manifested through situated practices and accessible dialogues.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the page for the combined panel on the 4S/EASST conference page. Here you can read who was involved and the agenda for the events.<br><br><br>This entry shares the resources used for the workshop element of the combined panel. These are a few fairly accessible steps of logging into a local server and writing a file but offering lots of Wiggle Room around them to make sense of and imagine these relations we encounter otherwise.<br><br><br>This entry links to the collective notes made during the workshop on the html file we edited in the workshop. On it are the reflections and sense-making of frictions and misfitting collaborators made when being in contact with the configurations, protocols and norms of network infrastructure.<br><br><img alt="This image shows the collective etherpad (left) and technical steps (right) for the workshop being projected for people to follow along." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/workshop_slides.png" target="_self"><br>
This image shows the collective etherpad (left) and technical steps (right) for the workshop being projected for people to follow along.<br><br><img alt="The Servpub server sat on a table with wires and cables in bundles and connected to the portable wifi router we used for local network connection." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/servpub_pi.png" target="_self"><br>
The Servpub server sat on a table with wires and cables in bundles and connected to the wifi router we used for local network.<br><br><img alt="In-grid's panel presentation with me (George) talking in front of a slide discussing collective wikis. Batool is sat in front of me with their back to the camera." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/in-grid_pres.png" target="_self"><br>
In-grid's panel presentation with me (George) talking in front of a slide discussing collective wikis. Batool is sat in front of me with their back to the camera.<br><br><img alt="Femke Snelting is stood presenting their work with TITiPI and enthusiastically discussing counter cloud imaginaries." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/titipi_pres.png" target="_self"><br>
Femke Snelting stood presenting their work with TITiPI and enthusiastically discussing counter cloud imaginaries.<br><br><img alt="Donna Holford-Lovell presenting their community work with NEoN Digital around space based digital inclusion" src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/neon_pres.png" target="_self"><br>
Donna Holford-Lovell presenting their community work with NEoN Digital around space based digital inclusion.<br><br><img alt="Júlia Nueno Guitart presenting her research around making infrastructures to help delivery driver unions combat efficient corporate platforms." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/julia_pres.png" target="_self"><br>
Júlia Nueno Guitart presenting her research around making infrastructures to help delivery driver unions combat efficient corporate platforms.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/collective-infrastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Collective Infrastructures/Collective Infrastructures.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:14:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/workshop_slides.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/media/workshop_slides.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving Cozy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This entry shares the installation of the Cozy-Cloud relaxation space that makes room for disabled people to be in touch with this crip network infrastructure. This cozy installation makes wiggle room for the embodied knowing and expertise of people to unfold through multisensory dialogues around these infrastructures. The Cozy-Cloud server is hosted using a VPN so that it can move around and bring with it this relaxation space to imagine crip networks infrastructures from. To manifest this cozy relaxation space, the server brings with it cozy-cloud cushions, stickers and a printable easy read version of the Cozy-Intentions.<br>This aims to offer up room around the Cozy-Cloud server, and outside of network space for other imaginaries of these infrastructures to emerge, specifically from relaxing, dream full and affirming backgrounds.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the Cozy-Intentions but formed into an easy read version that is printable. In the cozy-relaxation space a number of copies are printed out and placed around so that people can access the intentions of the server without ever going online.<br><br><img alt="An Inviting pile of Cozy-Cloud Pillows with the server snuggled up in the middle. The cloud pillows being extra fluffy and making room for cozy crip network imaginaries." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg" target="_self"><br>
An Inviting pile of Cozy-Cloud Pillows with the server snuggled up in the middle. The cloud pillows being extra fluffy and making room for cozy crip network imaginaries.<br><br><img alt="In among a cluster of Cozy-Cloud pillows, the small server's screen illuminates a hand reaching towards it. The screen they are reaching towards has written on it &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png" target="_self"><br>
In among a cluster of Cozy-Cloud pillows, the small server's screen illuminates a hand reaching towards it. The screen they are reaching towards has written on it "Let's Get Cozy".<br><br><img alt="A close up of the Cozy-Cloud server sitting within the cloud pillows with its background sharing the words &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;. The server sits of the tactile base with a textural cloud engraved on it and the words &quot;let's get cozy&quot; cut out of it.." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.jpeg" target="_self"> A close up of the Cozy-Cloud server sitting within the cloud pillows with its background sharing the words "Let's Get Cozy". The server sits on the tactile base with a textural cloud engraved on it and the words "let's get cozy" cut out of it.<br><br><img alt="The SVG file I used to engrave and cut out the tactile base for the server. It is a cloud with multiple layers and lines to add a tactile description of this form. Around the edges in cluncky placment are the words &quot;Let's-Get-Cozy&quot; outlined to be cut out. In the middle are four red circles for the server to be attached to it." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.svg" target="_self"> The SVG file I used to engrave and cut out the tactile base for the server. It is a cloud with multiple layers and lines to add a tactile description of this form. Around the edges in clunky placement are the words "Let's-Get-Cozy" outlined to be cut out. In the middle are four red circles for the server to be attached to it.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/serving-cozy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/Serving Cozy.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:13:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[En-crip-ing Time]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This entry shares En-crip-ing time, which is a crip infrastructure made in collaboration with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://marianamarangoni.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://marianamarangoni.com/" target="_self">Mariana Marangoni</a>. With En-crip-ing time we made room for crip time in network time, now and in the future. Through this we questioned the intimacies and care needed to not only manifest, but maintain crip infrastructures like these. This work was presented at Mesh Festival, as well as an essay about it published with Brand-New-Life Journal.<br>The En-crip-ing time infrastructure is run on the Cozy-Cloud server as a way to crip the internal clock and background of the server. It does this by poetically cripping the cron jobs (deterministic maintenance jobs) of the server to be chronic jobs (indeterminate, indefinite and intimate care). In this creative inquiry making room for Mariana and I to make sense of our misfitting within the configurations of network time, to then imagine how we want to poetically hack it now to imagine crips beyond its limits.<br><br><br><br>This entry share the live work that can be accessed online. This work is constantly changing shape and form so each time you visit it, it will perform another iteration of the En-crip-ed poem.<br><br><br>This entry shares the published essay around the work. It aims to bring together an accessible understanding of the technical steps needed to remake the work on your system, alongside the theoretical and conceptual ideas we have threaded throughout the piece.<br><br><br>This entry shares the event page for the presentation of the work for mesh festival 2024. This talk was the first presentation of En-crip-ing Time and shares our initial iteration alongside many other great PhD research projects.<br><br><img alt="A cover image by Mariana for Mesh festival. This is in grey scale and has a glitchy background of a distorted noisy image with random numbers, letters and symbols in lines across it. On top on this in clear black writing on a white background are the words &quot;En-crip-in Time&quot;." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" target="_self"> A cover image by Mariana for Mesh festival. This is in grey scale and has a glitchy background of a distorted noisy image with random numbers, letters and symbols in lines across it. On top of this in clear black writing on a white background are the words "En-crip-ing Time".<br><br><img alt="A snapshot of the live infrastructure and poem with the CSS working, as it will be different every time it is visited. The screen is filled with a mixture of fonts and placements in green, which hold different lines of the crip time poem. Here you can read lines like &quot;A home for us together&quot;, &quot;Of frictionless desire&quot;, as well as others. Their are bright pink almost unreadable bits of text which highlight the en-crip-ed lines of the poem." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.png" target="_self"> A snapshot of the live infrastructure and poem with the CSS working, as it will be different every time it is visited. The screen is filled with a mixture of fonts and placements in green, which hold different lines of the crip time poem. Here you can read lines like "A home for us together", "Of frictionless desire", as well as others. There are bright pink almost unreadable bits of text which highlight the en-crip-ed lines of the poem.<br><br><img alt="A web browser with the poem and its code showing side by side. Here I am sharing how in-between the the lines of the code/poem their are comments reflecting on the crip times of care that made this infrastructure possible." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.png" target="_self"> A web browser with the poem and its code showing side by side. Here I am sharing how in-between the lines of the code/poem there are comments reflecting on the crip times of care and intimacy that made this infrastructure possible.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/en-crip-ing-time.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/En-crip-ing_time/En-crip-ing Time.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:12:21 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-ish]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Cozy-ish is the first theme for the Cozy-Cloud blog which ran with a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://picocms.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://picocms.org/" target="_self">Pico CMS</a>. This theme was initially made to hold the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-Intentions.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Intentions</a> as well as some docs for the early setup. It is made to be an accessible, minimal and Cozy aesthetic to host the intentions and docs of the server. It is an adapted version of Winnie Soon's <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://gitlab.com/siusoon/soonish/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://gitlab.com/siusoon/soonish/" target="_self"><em></em></a>Soonish and adds a few minor edits to make it a lil more cozy.<br><br><br><img alt="A screen shot of the Cozy-ish Theme, which has a orange to yellow gradient at the bottom which gently fade to off white at the top. The theme has a funky title font in the top right, a clear simple menu on the left with an arrow point to the current file. The page content is held in the middle and scrolls out of a fade from the bottom." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" target="_self"> A screenshot of the Cozy-ish Theme, which has a orange to yellow gradient at the bottom which gently fade to off-white at the top. The theme has a funky title font in the top right, a clear simple menu on the left with an arrow point to the current file. The page content is held in the middle and scrolls out of a fade from the bottom.<br><br><br>This theme is free to use and modify. To test it out follow the docs on the Pico website.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/cozy-ish.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-ish/Cozy-ish.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:11:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-Intentions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This page brings together the cozy intentions for the cozy-cloud.net. This is to give an understanding of how and why this crip server came to be and to share some of the desires we have when making an affirmative digital space that orients from disabled people, affirming politics and embodied expertise.<br>These intentions take the format of image and alt text pairs, each pair offering up their own thread to be followed, weaving together a story that figures out the cozy-cloud. In a crip move, these intentions entangle together the affective sense making and their knowledges, within political and relational imaginaries that aim to transform the capacities and imaginaries of sociotechnical infrastructures.<br>Working poetically with Alt texts these intentions emphasis how access practices have the capacity to be joyful, fun and cozy, not the determinate awkward and painful tasks they are often made out to be.<br>These intentions ask: If we as disabled x neurodiverse x chronically ill people have the capacity to shape digital infrastructure and the ways our communities meet online from our backgrounds and embodied expertise, what could that be and feel like?<br><br><br><img alt="Furry text saying &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;, welcomes you to get cozy! This is an enthusiastic and loving message reminding you to get cozy in what ever way you are able to. Many times (not always) when we can't get cozy,our experience it is telling us that something might be wrong systemically. This text asks us to think, what would enable me to get cozy? What relations would have to change for us to actually be cozy? By trying to get cozy we start to make these transformations, so settle in and lets get cozy." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" target="_self"><br><br>Furry text saying "Let's Get Cozy", welcomes you to get cozy! This is an enthusiastic and loving message reminding you to get cozy in which ever way you desire to.<br>Many times (not always) when we can't get cozy, our sense making of misfitting here is telling us that something might be wrong systemically. This text asks us to think, what would make room for me to get cozy? What relations would have to change for me to actually be cozy? By trying to get cozy you start to make these transformations, so settle in and lets get cozy.<br><br><br><img alt="A cloud sits unsure on a day with mixed weather. It feels sensitive to the gusts and gales of bigger clouds and so searches for a sheltered valley to get cozy and come back to earth. It asks us to think about how we feel in the cloud. When we are using cloud enabled devices, like streaming, cloud drives or social platforms do we feel a connection to what it is we are doing? What would it feel like to be in touch and get cozy with our digital infrastructures." src="https://configure-able.info/my-projects-🗃/cozy-cloud/previs/imgs/cloud5.png" target="_self"><br><br>A cloud sits unsure on a day with mixed weather. It feels sensitive to the gusts and gales of bigger clouds and so searches for a sheltered valley to get cozy and come back to earth.<br>It asks us to think about how we feel in the cloud. When we are using cloud enabled devices, like streaming, cloud drives or social platforms do we feel a connection to what it is we are doing? What would it feel like to be in touch and get cozy with our digital infrastructures.<br><br><br><img alt="The cozy-cloud sits within a ring of furry and cozy text saying &quot;Less Cloud - More Cozy&quot;. It feels warmth in knowing its energies are conserved for doing cozy things and not being a part of deadly storms elsewhere. It asks us to think about less dispersion of our digital selves into a commercial cloud that displaces the harms of digital infrastructures out of reach. How can you settle in, keep ourselves close and feel out how cozy our clouds could be?" src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.png" target="_self"><br><br>The cozy-cloud sits within a ring of furry and cozy text saying "Less Cloud - More Cozy". It feels warmth in knowing its energies are conserved for doing cozy things and not being a part of deadly storms elsewhere.<br>It asks us to think about less dispersion of our digital selves into a commercial cloud that displaces the harms of digital infrastructures out of reach. How can we settle in, keep ourselves close and feel out how cozy our clouds could be?<br><br><br><img alt="Slightly clumsy but cute furry text says &quot;Clouds are finite :( Coziness can be infinite!&quot;. It sits slightly slumped to one side, exhausted with keeping up with the continuous expansion. It helps us to reflect on the limitations of computing and cloud infrastructures, the consumption of fossil fuels, rare minerals and people's labour to try to maintain the unmaintainable infinite growth. What if we centre our clouds on other infinities of care, compassion and coziness? What would network infrastructures feel like and have the capacity for through these more intimate modes?" src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.png" target="_self"><br><br>Slightly clumsy but cute furry text says "Clouds are finite :( Coziness can be infinite!". It sits slightly slumped to one side, exhausted with keeping up with the continuous expansion.<br>It helps us to reflect on the limitations of computing and cloud infrastructures, the consumption of fossil fuels, rare minerals and people's labor to try to maintain the unmaintainable infinite growth. What if we center our clouds on other infinities of care, compassion and coziness? What would network infrastructures feel like and have the capacity for through these more intimate modes?<br><br><br><img alt="A map of arpnet, an early computer network infrastructure produced by the us gov/army is transformed into a cozy-constellation. This transformation resembles the way digital networks have a history of control of space (both physical and virtual) through force and how we have to transform them with care and coziness. It asks us how we could imagine networks in retreat from these histories of mapping, taxonomy and capture to instead feel out what their affirmative promise could be." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png" target="_self"><br><br>A map of arpnet, an early computer network produced by the us gov/army is transformed into a cozy-constellation. This transformation resembles the way digital networks have a history of control of space (both physical and virtual) through force and how we have to transform them with care and coziness.<br>It asks us how we could imagine networks in retreat from these histories of mapping, taxonomy and capture to instead feel out what their affirmative promise could be when embracing coziness.<br><br><br><img alt="A png of a cloud with transparent background so that it appears comfortable and confident wherever it is displayed. The cloud presents so light and pretty floating on the page, but still on the edge of creating a little drizzle. The image itself is on a free license so is free like a cloud! It reminds us what a cloud looks like and what it has capacity for. The computational infrastructures that make up the commercial cloud could never be so light nor caring to our ecology and body/minds. What metaphors or analogies do you desire our network infrastructures to be performed through? How would you transform and shape them by putting these infrastructure in your own terms." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.png" target="_self"><br><br>A png of a cloud with transparent background so that it appears comfortable and confident wherever it is displayed. The cloud presents so light and pretty floating on the page, but still on the edge of creating a little drizzle. The image itself is on a free license so is free like a cloud!<br>It reminds us what a cloud looks like and what it has capacity for. The computational infrastructures that make up the commercial cloud could never be so light nor caring to our ecology and body/minds. What metaphors or analogies do you desire our network infrastructures to be performed through? How would you transform and shape them by putting these infrastructure in your own terms.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/Cozy-Intentions.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:10:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disobedient Access Requests]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This disobedient access request came about through a commissioned audio piece for the Tate Modern and their Electric Dreams FM radio show. This radio show and audio pieces were supposed to create an accessible accompaniment to the main in person Electric Dreams exhibition. Through this commission I started an inquiry to feel out the limits of these institutions and the capacities a disobedient access request has to disrupt, (dis)orient and refuse institution's normalized configurations.<br>The pairing of the audio piece and the access request act together as a refusal of big tech through both artistic and creative methods, as well as through direct actions and hacking. The audio piece refuses to situate itself within the normalized narratives of technology and asks how crip studies can unfold other relations and connections to technologies, our bodyminds, ecologies and embodied sense-making. Through this poetic recipe bringing together politics and imaginaries that manifest intimate practices that aims to affirm lives through affirmation and care. The accompanying disobedient access request refusing to be captured by the Big Tech Cloud, and in doing so questioning what the capacities access making and knowledge have to directly challenge and shape the configurations and infrastructures of institutions.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the audio piece on the Electric Dreams FM website. This holds the edited down poem and recording for you to listen to or read.<br><br><img alt="A screen shot from a contract with the Tate displaying a &quot;Note&quot; disclaiming it cannot be shared on platforms run by Google LLC" src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png" target="_self"> An image that shares a screenshot of a contract and how the access request I made brought into contracts my refusal of Big Tech platforms (Google) with my media. This was only a small gesture but aimed to wiggle room towards the promise of access as a practice which can retreat from these normalized violent institutions and configurations.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/disobedient-access-requests.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Disobedient Access Requests.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:09:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>These collaborative workshops were organized with NEoN digital to share some queer, feminist and crip practices towards network infrastructures. In these workshops I collaborated with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://meltionary.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://meltionary.com/" target="_self">MELT</a> and members of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://systerserver.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://systerserver.net/" target="_self">SysterServer</a> to run two workshops and share how collective access can be understood and actioned within digital networks.<br>Due to a desire to run these workshops online and through Free Libre Open Source Softwar (FLOSS) these workshops also offered up a number of misfittings around how FLOSS imagines and makes room for accessibility. This came from the realization that in the context of this workshop where we needed automated captions, there were no easily accessible FLOSS softwares that could meet these requirements. From this misfitting we emerged an understanding of how FLOSS does not make room or time for accessibility, neither does it imagine it as essential.<br>From this friction the workshop also made Wiggle Room to improvise and hack together an automated live captioning setup that made room for everyone to meet through FLOSS online, but also for people to setup their own local live captioning software on their computer if they wanted it. This improvised setup even though being on individuals computers was intentionally felt out and actioned through collective sense making and interdependent action.<br><br><br><br>This entry shares the event page for the workshop. This holds more information on who was there, what they presented and more details on the event.<br><br><br>This entry shares the improvised auto-captioning software that we hacked together for the workshop so that we could try to make the workshops FLOSS video calls accessible.<br><br><img alt="The event poster for &quot;Configure-Able Infrastructures&quot;. It has a blurry background of greens, reds and blues. On top are a number of boxes outlined and linked by white dashed lines and filed with white text. The top box has the title of the event, and then connects to others, one holding &quot;A set of workshops/talks creating dialogues around what configure-able infra can be&quot;, another stating &quot;Melt, 19th July, Access sparks: incendiary emails for change making&quot; and another with &quot;Syster Server 2nd Aug, Organizing the anarcha feminist cyborg hacker uprising&quot;" src="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" target="_self"> The event poster for "Configure-Able Infrastructures". It has a blurry background of greens, reds and blues. On top are a number of boxes outlined and linked by white dashed lines and filed with white text. The top box has the title of the event, and then connects to others, one holding "A set of workshops/talks creating dialogues around what configure-able infra can be", another stating "Melt, 19th July, Access sparks: incendiary emails for change making" and another with "SysterServer 2nd Aug, Organizing the anarcha feminist cyborg hacker uprising"<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:09:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates an institution wiggling and all of its supports at angles to their normalized straight orientation" src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries share how critical access making and resulting knowledges offer up Wiggle Room for misfitting of the prescribed plans of configurations. These inquiries focus specifically on how frictions access knowledges make sense of the limits and capacities of institutes, infrastructures and relations. In this movement disobediently forming counter imaginaries and improvise infrastructures through direct actions of independent access making.<br><br><br><br>This entry reflects on the running of the Configure-Able Infrastructures workshops at NEoN Digital which shared practices around crip and feminist networks. Organizing this accessible workshop through Free Libra Open Source Software (FLOSS) offered up room for collaborators to critique the normalized configurations, "default settings" and ableist assumptions of FLOSS through access making and knowing. In practice, it also shares how these frictions collaborations improvise crip FLOSS infrastructures for automated captions then and there.<br><br><br>This entry shares how access requesting to institutions, such as the Tate, can make Wiggle Room within configurations and their sedimented infrastructures and politics. Through practices of disobedient access requests, this inquiry shares how access making feels out and builds up the relational capacity to reconfigure institutional infrastructures and deviate them from their normalized violent dependencies.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:08:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disobedient Action Research Methods]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br><br>The indeterminate diagram above represents this project's disobedient methodology as it aims to (dis)orient the standardized and prescribed methods of configuration. Each time you visit this page, and every time you click on the diagram, it creates a different composition of actions, sense makings and wiggling of room that this disobedient crip methodology entices. Visually it forms loops and cycles of the icons and terms of this research connected into indeterminate compositions. Each iteration has a generated Alt-text containing the syntax for the diagram, and which can be interpreted in a similarly playful way. The Alt-text is attached to the &lt;div&gt; with the .mermaid class.<br>This code is an edit of another work/performance called <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" target="_self">Pad2Party</a> that Sunni Liao, Yewen Jin and I made as part or <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" target="_self">RealBodies 2.1</a> with In-grid collective.<br><br><br>For this project I have taken on a Disobedient Action Research Methodology. As the above texture and indeterminate diagram tries to highlight, this methodology disobediently refuses to be generalized or normalized into set operations. Instead this project's Trans*methods make wiggle room for bodyminds to access, be in touch with and shape the sociotechnical infrastructures and matters they are impacted by and misfit within. <br>To build up my projects Disobedient Action Research methodology I work with the debugging methods of TiTIPi (Pritchard et al., 2021) and build it up with misfitting methods of Carla Rice et al. (2024) to ask what room can collective embodied inquiries make within infrastructuring. With this methodology I make room to be intimate with and build up collective expertise that question what affirmative infrastructures, practices and relations are within reach socially and technically through independent action. Through this disobedient methodology I re-frame what actions can be taken within academic research, moving to make-sense of what lives are livable beyond assimilation norms of access, organization and infrastructures on institutional terms.<br>Through my Trans*methodology my research is shaped through collective practices, debugging, terminal consoles, bank interfaces, parties, workshops, messaging stickers, VPN's and soft cushions. Coalescing together these many surfaces, textures and tables of research collaborators and I made sense of how our technical practices could be shaped by our backgrounds, expertise and feelings. Through this methodology collectively figuring out what our affirmative community infrastructures are through unfolding actions of access making.<br><br><br>These protocols offer up some of the ways my disobedient methods have unfolded within this research project. These protocols themselves are loose mappings of what happened in this research and offers up how these methods are improvisable, situated, and shaped by their actions.<br><br><br>Practicing Protocols shares how these methods unfolded into a set of accessible workshops that questioned the configurations of network infrastructures. These workshops made wiggle room for people to make sense of and shape network infrastructures through their embodied expertise and situated practices. <br>This protocol unfolded from the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Collective Infrastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/collective-infrastructures/collective-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Collective Infrastructures</a> combined panel, and at the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving_In-grid/Serving In-grid.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/serving_in-grid/serving-in-grid.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid</a> workshop. These workshop inquiries made wiggle room for us to unfold collective expertise around our misfitting within the normalized network configurations we have inherited. From misfitting moving to form counter figures, relations and imaginaries for the affirming network infrastructures we desire now.<br><br>This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol took action. It moves from accessible technical documentation that helped us make sense of our embodied misfitting within these configurations. From this misfitting forming our own situated figures and terms for how we want to practice this infrastructure locally.<br><br><br>Improvising Floss Protocols shares how these methods unfolded around making access within FLOSS technologies throughout this research. This protocol offers up how collaborators and I wiggled room between the misfitting of FLOSS and our access knowledges to improvise our own access technologies. Through these practices of access making, making sense of the limits and capacities of access within FLOSS.<br>This protocol unfolded from the the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop</a> I organised with NEoN digital, making the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-ish.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/cozy-ish.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-ish</a> and <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy Night and Day.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/cozy-night-and-day.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy Night and Day</a> themes, as well as manifesting the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-Intentions.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Intentions</a> and <a class="internal-link" data-href="Serving Cozy.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/serving-cozy.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving Cozy install</a>. This protocol unfolded from the wiggled room made within FLOSS technologies for them to be shaped by and affirm our access knowledges, practices and desires.<br><br> This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol made sense of how FLOSS technologies we had in reach misfitted with the access knowledges and practices of the group. From this misfitting moving to wiggle room, improvise and shape the imaginaries and capacities of FLOSS through collective practices of access making.<br><br><br>(Dis)orienting Protocols shares how these methods unfolded when being in touch with and disobediently trying to shape institutional configurations and organization processes. This protocol offers up how collaborators and I made wiggle room around inflexible institutional norms to (dis)orient them towards our backgrounds, politics and desires for the future. <br>This protocol unfolded from collaborating on In-grid's organizational practices that are shared in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="In-fra Processing.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-fra-processing/in-fra-processing.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-fra Processing</a> entry. The protocol was also shaped by the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Disobedient Access Requests.md" href="https://configure-able.info/configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/disobedient-access-requests.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Disobedient Access Requests</a> that I made towards the Tate's configurations and within <a class="internal-link" data-href="En-crip-ing Time.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/en-crip-ing-time.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">En-crip-ing Time's</a> refusal of the configurations of network time and intimacies.<br><br>This mapping above gives shape to how this protocol (dis)oriented configurations by making wiggle room to feel out our frictions with the sedimented norms of institutions and their organization. From this wiggle room starting to unfold and form our own organizational practices, desires and imaginaries for how we want to orient and improvise them locally. ]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/methods.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Methods.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:52:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><img src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/layers.svg" target="_self"><br>This repo shares the methods and practice that unfolded from the "Configure-able Infrastructures" research project. This research offers up how critical access informed practices made wiggle room for our embodied expertise of misfitting to shape our collective organizing and infrastructuring. Through these methods and practices making accessible the technologies that support us, so that we can challenge and (dis)orient the normalizing configurations, relations and politics we have inherited with them.<br><br><br>This research project engages crip and queer methods to experimentally and collectively (dis)orient the norms and limits of network infrastructure towards more life-affirming possibilities. Building on feminist Science and Technology Studies (STS) (Suchman 2012; Amoore 2020), the thesis interrogates the deterministic configurations, prescribed roles and relations that hold organizational and network infrastructures in place, while taking up crip and queer methods to further examine how such infrastructures create hard systems that reinforce ableist conceptions of use, access, and knowledge. Through the disobedient methods, practices and politics offered by Disability Justice, crip and queer theory (Ahmed 2006; Kafer 2013; 2023; Hamraie 2017; 2023; Rice et al. 2024), I question the inherited figures of configuration (such as “users”) and develop alternative ways of manifesting systems that are people-powered and center the needs of collectives instead of configuring people into infrastructural elements. Combining critique with practice, the thesis generates collective methods for making wiggle room (Ahmed 2014; Pritchard 2022) in network infrastructures for soft, situated, indeterminate, and misfitting embodied knowledges and emergent forms of collective life.<br>My research undertakes three inquiries into what configure-able infrastructures can be in action. Rather than abstract systems, these collective infrastructuring practices are situated, shaped, and manifested by specific contexts and bodies. In the first inquiry, I reflect on my practices and experiences of access making, examining how the misfitting of collective access and access riders can shape configurations from sites of friction. The second inquiry is grounded in collaboration with In-grid collective, a Trans*Feminist digital arts collective, exploring how critical access can inform collective intersectional practice from the outset, instead of being added on afterward. The final inquiry manifests crip network infrastructures by and for disabled people through work on the Cozy-Cloud, a crip server and collaborative practice. By making room for disabled people to form their own expertise, practices and knowledge of network infrastructures, it becomes possible to disorient the sedimented configurations of hard technical systems, and to form counter configure-able infrastructures that unfold from embodied knowledges, experiences and collective practices.<br>From these inquiries, the thesis offers methods and practices for disorienting the normative configurations of infrastructures through crip and queer forms of “misfitting” when accessing and using these systems, and the collective sense-making that unfolds. By making wiggle room around misfitting, this research not only validates but builds from the embodied knowing and frictious expertise of systems. These inquiries share how collaborators and I have started to make room for our own configure-able infrastructures through interdependent practices of access making and knowing.<br>This thesis does not offer solutions or cures to the misfitting of network infrastructures, collective organizing and their configurational methods, but surfaces how crip and queer methods can make room for the frictions of misfitting expertise and practices that can take them off course, and towards the affirming futures we desire now.]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:53:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/layers.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/media/icons/layers.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy Night and Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This entry shares the current theme for the Cozy-Cloud website, which works with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.bludit.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.bludit.com/" target="_self">Bludit CMS</a>. It is made to be very light weight so that those with limited connection and unstable internet networks can still access the site. The theme also utilizes tags/code to activate Screen Readers and which make the information of the website much more accessible to those who use assistive tools to view online media.<br>This website and theme make room to bring together the work of the Cozy-Cloud by offering up lightweight and accessible introductions to each work and infrastructure. It is also a move towards building up the capacities of the Cozy-Cloud so that it can be accessible to more collaborations and exchanges through this more accessible CMS.<br><br><br><br> This entry shares the git for the theme for the website so that it can be used by others and potentially be edited from into other iterations. It is a minimal and fairly accessible theme to set up and edit.<br><br><br>This entry links through to the Cozy-Cloud page where I share how to install the Cozy Night+Day theme on your own blog hosted with Bludit.<br><br> <img alt="An image sharing the day layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme is in light mode and has a gradient background, going from warm yellow at the bottom to off white at the top. On the top left is the title of the site saying &quot;Cozy-Cloud&quot; in a bold black font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is the Cozy-Cloud icon appearing cozy and welcoming." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" target="_self"><br>
An image sharing the day layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme is in light mode and has a gradient background, going from warm yellow at the bottom to off white at the top. On the top left is the title of the site saying "Cozy-Cloud" in a bold black font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is the Cozy-Cloud icon appearing cozy and welcoming.<br><br> <img alt="An image sharing the night layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme is in dark mode and has a gradient background, going from dark red/purple at the bottom to warm red/orange at the top. In the top left is the title of the site saying &quot;Cozy-Cloud&quot; in a bold white font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is the Cozy-Cloud icon appearing cozy and welcoming." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.png" target="_self"><br>
An image sharing the night layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme is in dark mode and has a gradient background, going from dark red/purple at the bottom to warm red/orange at the top. In the top left is the title of the site saying "Cozy-Cloud" in a bold white font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is the Cozy-Cloud icon appearing cozy and welcoming.<br><br><br>This entry shares the HTML syntax and tags that make the content of the page accessible to screen readers. There is more to making this theme and the websites content more accessible, but this is the main improvement/learning from this iteration.<br>&lt;article&gt; &lt;h2 class="mb2"&gt; page title &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; by &lt;span class="author"&gt;author&lt;/span on &lt;time class="dateline"&gt;date&lt;/time &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cover"&gt; &lt;img src="./cover.img" alt="a cute cover image"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Content &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
<br><br> <img alt="An image sharing how the website activates and can be accessed with a screen reader. This is the default Firefox screen reader and shares the page en-crip-ing time page with the access menu on the left, letting people adapt how they can view the websites information." src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.png" target="_self"><br>
An image sharing how the website activates and can be accessed with a screen reader. This is the default Firefox screen reader and shares the blog page about En-crip-ing time with the access menu on the left, letting people adapt how they can view the websites information.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/cozy-night-and-day.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy_Night+Day/Cozy Night and Day.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:53:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[References]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>A small selection of the references that have informed this work &lt;3<br><br>Amoore, Louise. 2020. Cloud Ethics: Algorithms and the Attributes of Ourselves and Others. Duke University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.1215/9781478009276" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.1215/9781478009276</a>.<br><br>Ahmed, Sara. 2006. Queer Phenomenology: Orientations, Objects, Others. Duke University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv125jk6w" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv125jk6w</a>.<br><br>Ahmed, Sarah. 2014. ‘Wiggle Room’. Feministkilljoys, September 28. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/" target="_self">https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/</a>.<br><br>Ahmed, Sara. 2016. Living a Feminist Life. Duke University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv11g9836" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv11g9836</a>.<br><br>Gearty, Margaret Rose, and Judi Marshall. 2021. ‘Living Life as Inquiry – a Systemic Practice for Change Agents’. Systemic Practice and Action Research 34 (4): 441–62. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4</a>.<br><br>Hamraie, Aimi. 2017. Building Access: Universal Design and the Politics of Disability. Universal Design and the Politics of Disability. University of Minnesota Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6</a>.<br><br>Hamraie, Aimi. 2023. ‘Critical Access Studies’. October 26. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tz7vQ89ElDk" target="_self">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tz7vQ89ElDk</a>.<br><br>Hamraie, Aimi. 2023. ‘Crip Making’. In Crip Authorship: Disability as Method, edited by Mara Mills and Rebecca Sanchez. New York University Press.<br><br>Hamraie, Aimi, and Kelly Fritsch. 2019. ‘Crip Technoscience Manifesto’. Catalyst: Feminism, Theory, Technoscience 5 (1): 1. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607</a>.<br><br>Kafai, Shayda. 2021. Crip Kinship: The Disability Justice &amp; Art Activism of Sins Invalid. Arsenal Pulp Press.<br><br>Kafer, Alison. 2013. Feminist, Queer, Crip. Indiana University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt16gz79x" target="_self">https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt16gz79x</a>.<br><br>Kafer, Alison. 2017. ‘Health Rebels: A Crip Manifesto for Social Justice’. April 6. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YqcOUD1pBKw" target="_self">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YqcOUD1pBKw</a>.<br><br>Kafer, Alison. 2023. ‘Manifesting Manifestos’. In Crip Authorship: Disability as Method, edited by Mara Mills and Rebecca Sanchez. New York University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.18574/nyu/9781479819386.001.0001" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.18574/nyu/9781479819386.001.0001</a>.<br><br>Maier, Sophia, V. Jo Hsu, Christina V Cedillo, and M. Remi Yergeau. 2020. GET THE FRAC IN! Or, The Fractal Many-Festo: A (Trans)(Crip)T1. August 12. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/" target="_self">https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/</a>.<br><br>Mingus, Mia. 2017. ‘Access Intimacy, Interdependence and Disability Justice’. Leaving Evidence, April 12. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/" target="_self">https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/</a>.<br><br>Pritchard, Helen V. 2022. ‘Wiggleroom’. April 28. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom" target="_self">https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom</a>.<br><br>Pritchard, H., J. Rocha, and F. Snelting. 2021. ‘We Have Always Been Geohackers’. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://hdl.handle.net/10026.1/18174" target="_self">http://hdl.handle.net/10026.1/18174</a>.<br><br>Rice, Carla, Eliza Chandler, Fady Shanouda, Chelsea Temple Jones, and Ingrid Mündel. 2024. ‘Misfits Meet Art and Technology: Cripping Transmethodologies’. Cultural Studies ↔ Critical Methodologies 24 (4): 219–31. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.1177/15327086241234705" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.1177/15327086241234705</a>.<br><br>Suchman, Lucy. 2012. ‘Configuration’. In Inventive Methods, 0 ed., edited by Celia Lury and Nina Wakeford. Routledge. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203854921" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203854921</a>.<br><br>TITiPI, Stevie Ango, and Clyde Lepage. 2022. ‘Infrables’. May 18. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Unfolding:Infrables" target="_self">https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Unfolding:Infrables</a>.]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/about/references.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/About/References.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:54:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-Cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a cloud with a small grin and a big cozy cup of a warm drink of your choice" src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg" target="_self"><br>These inquiries offer up how the Cozy-Cloud made wiggle room for a crip server and network infrastructuring practices to unfold emergent actions of access making. Through these actions making sense of the misfitting between the politics and practices of disability justice and those sedimented within network configurations. These inquiries take the form of solo and collaborative action research and creative technical practices of access making. These works were presented at Mesh Festival and published in Brand-New-Life journal as well as informed by a residency at the BDFI.<br>These inquiries question how we came together through crip intimacies and access practices to make-sense of the misfitting that we felt within the prescribed configurations of network infrastructures. By wiggling room for these frictions we independently figured out what life affirming network infrastructures, practices and relations we desired within and beyond these systems. In this approach bringing focus to how disabled experiences, embodied expertise and independent practices offer up an ambivalent relationship to infrastructures that can (dis)orient the normalizing network configurations towards ones that are shaped by the bodyminds they impact and misfit.<br><br><br><br> This entry shares the cozy installation and relaxation space for the Cozy-Cloud. It brings together the soft cozy-cloud cushions, the easy read cozy intentions and the tactile server base.<br><br><br> This entry shares the first theme for the Cozy-Cloud's website. Working with Pico, this light weight and (somewhat) accessible blog hosted the server's original Cozy-Intention.<br><br><br>This entry shares the cozy intentions for the cozy-cloud. These intentions both shape the promise and orientation of this crip network infrastructure. In their medium these intentions also offer up how Alt texts and network access practices can make room to imagine this infrastructure through care, joy and creativity.<br><br><br> This entry shares the crip infrastructure made in collaboration with Mariana Marangoni called En-crip-ing Time. This infrastructure crips the Cozy-Cloud server's clock and manifests poetic server protocols that offer up how networks might be (dis)oriented through crip time and intimate maintenance practices.<br><br><br> This entry shares the latest theme for the Cozy-Cloud blog and which focuses on being much more accessible. This was to try to make it more accessible to collaborations, but also for the content to be picked up more clearly by screen readers and access technologies.<br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:17:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-Docs]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>These docs unfolded from In-grid's collaboration during the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Main_Page" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Main_Page" target="_self">Servpub</a> project. These docs were made during the infrastructuring process to help us share and explain how to setup the back-end VPN and server infrastructure with collaborators. Through this process we questioned how the norms of docs and of sharing technical knowledge were encoded and formatted to be only accessible by certain bodies, backgrounds and knowledges. From our sense making of misfitting within these norms, we started to question how we desired to overcome these barriers through collective access making.<br>To counter the barriers of access within these docs and technical network practices we were informed through Kelsie Acton's framing of Plain Language For Disability. Through Acton's understanding and approach to plain language we began to question how technical language can start to move towards a plain language version. This version making room within these technical norms not only for people to access and make sense of them in action, but for their sedimented norms to be disoriented and manifested from a plurality of embodied expertise and backgrounds.<br>It also has to be said that these docs are not "Plain Language" in the sense that Acton's work would present it, but are instead a step towards plain language from technical docs. In this motion, similarly this was also a place to start to inform In-grid (a majority non-disabled collective) to be informed by and in touch with critical access practices and discourse. So even though these docs are not the most accessible plain language, they do describe this first contact and movement towards more accessible and disputable technical discourse within In-grid.<br><br><br><br> This entry shares a snapshot of the intro page of the accessible technical Docs In-grid put together. It links out to the rest of the Docs online, but also offers up our notes on making more accessible docs and being inform by Kelsie Acton's Plain Language<br><br><img alt="An image from a workshop In-grid did at Transmediale Content Form where members of In-gird are presenting the docs and a diagram of the network. Katie, Becky and I are sat at a table with our backs to the camera pointing to a screen behind us with the diagram of the network on it." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png" target="_self"><br>
An image from a workshop In-grid did at Transmediale Content Form where members are presenting the docs and a diagram of the network. Katie Tindle, Becky Aston and I are sat at a table with our backs to the camera pointing to a screen behind us with the diagram of the network on it.<br><br><img alt="A Diagram of the Servpub network. It has a purple and pink background with with a green and yellow diagram made up of text, squares and lines. These represent how collectives, hardware and networks come together into this publishing infrastructure." src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" target="_self"><br>
A diagram made by Batool Desouky for the front page of the docs which shares how the Servpub network is configured. <br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../../Practice.md" href="https://configure-able.info/practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;/Practice/</a><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-Grid's In-frastructures/</a>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/in-docs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/In-Docs.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:49:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://configure-able.info/in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Processing Misfitting]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>This Protocol aims to make room for groups and individuals to make-sense of their misfitting within system and their configurations. This protocol does this by distributing the expertise of systems to the community that it is situated within through access practices that aim to make these systems more disputable, improvisable and affirming to those impacted by them. <br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/methods/processing-misfitting.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/methods/Processing Misfitting.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:14:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frictious Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>]]></description><link>https://configure-able.info/methods/frictious-infrastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/methods/Frictious Infrastructures.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[George Simms]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:48:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>