<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Wiki]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.svg</url><title>Wiki</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:55:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:55:42 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Glossary]]></title><description><![CDATA[This Glossary aims to share some of the terms and words used to shape this research. These descriptions aim to accessibly offer up how this research works with crip and queer feminist theory to form critical access informed approaches to community infrastructuring. These terms help to understand how this research makes sense of the many bodies, technologies and relations that it is in touch with. This glossary brings focus to how this research has brought together, moved through and made friction with the unknowable and unpredictable actions of community infrastructuring. Friction is a process of access making. It brings together both the making sense of when access is needed or when friction is felt, with the action of making access through friction, making request and transforming your feelings into change. In crip theory there is also this word play with friction, that even though there can be pain from frictions, there is also a possibility for pleasure and joy, which is often never imagined. Friction in this research is then understood as being a place of joyous, pleasurable and embodied access making in action. Wiggle Room builds from Friction to pose a process of friction making. This process is specifically around the categories and relations that people are prescribed by the norms of systems. With Wiggle Room this process of friction making takes on the approach of feeling out how determined categories and relations misfit the bodies they impact. From this sense making asking how these impacted bodies can Wiggle Room within these determined relations and towards ones that are shaped by and affirm the lives they hold. The Table in this research is a metaphor for the institutional norms that have been gradually sedimented into determined and inflexible relations. Tables in this research are take many forms, from my desk, to excell tables, to kitchen tables, to interview tables, operating tables, and to the grid of cells on a video call. Working with the Table this research asks how these institutes and norms make room for us to be together, and how we can also start to push back and bring these norms in touch with out own tables and relations. The Crip Table builds from the Table to imagine what a Table shaped by crip politics and community would feel like. With this the Crip Table questions how tables can not be held in place, or oriented towards determined bodies and relations, but instead towards promises of life affirmation and justice. The Crip Table making room to imagine how systems, infrastructures and their of inflexible relations can be flexible and shaped by the bodies they impact and are in touch with. The Bodily Horizon in this research makes present and situates how bodies are in relation with things around them. The Bodily Horizon makes room to question what is within reach, what can be changed, and what limits and capacities there are within the actions we take. It both makes sense of the frictions of the present while making room to question what the body wants to be within reach of in the future. With the Bodily Horizon here, it is then a body that is in motion, one that feels and makes change, and one that sits between the present and the future. The Bodymind in crip theory, is the refusal of the split between the mind and body made within western medicine and philosophy. It instead brings together the body and the mind in a way that brings to the foreground the body and it sense making, whilst still caring for the mind. In the breaking down of boundaries between mind and body is also extended in this research to break down the boundaries between bodies and the relations that impact them. In this orientation the Bodymind questions the determined ways bodies, minds and their matters are separated, and makes room to feel how they might come together and transform relations through their entangled sense making. Ahmed, Sara. 2006. Queer Phenomenology: Orientations, Objects, Others. Duke University Press. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv125jk6w" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv125jk6w</a>.<br>Hamraie, Aimi, and Kelly Fritsch. 2019. ‘Crip Technoscience Manifesto’. Catalyst: Feminism, Theory, Technoscience 5 (1): 1. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607</a>.Kafer, Alison. 2013. Feminist, Queer, Crip. Indiana University Press. (p 47-69)<br>Pritchard, Helen V. 2022. ‘Wiggleroom’. April 28. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom" target="_self">https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom</a>.<br>Sarah Ahmed. 2014. ‘Wiggle Room’. Feministkilljoys, September 28. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/" target="_self">https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/</a>.Kafer, Alison. 2013. Feminist, Queer, Crip. Indiana University Press. (p 47-69)<br>Hamraie, Aimi, and Kelly Fritsch. 2019. ‘Crip Technoscience Manifesto’. Catalyst: Feminism, Theory, Technoscience 5 (1): 1. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.28968/cftt.v5i1.29607</a>.]]></description><link>glossary.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Glossary.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:16:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Background to Retreat]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a picture frame hanging from a thread. There is no canvas in the frame making room for a scene to be set." src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/background.svg" target="_self">This section disobediently shares the background to these inquiries. These are the bits that don't quite fit into the "straight" line of my research, but do give shape and contour to what this research is in retreat of. These inquiries in form are practice based sense makings of AI and automated decision making. Through this practice aiming to query how these computational and infrastructural norms are encoded, sedimented and configured into prescribed algorithms that orient and model problems to be solved through divisive and penalising logics.Multi column This entry shares a collaborative dataset that I made with others to make-sense of how to entangle and situate the often isolated data of datasets. This entry shares an inquiry into how a type of AI called Reinforcement-Learning (RL) can make room for collaborative agents to represent their environment to one another. This entry shares an inquiry into other sorts of emergent intelligence systems called Artificial Immune (AI) systems, through a collaboration I undertook with Sissle Marie Tonn Might add more /\<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;- Back to Practice</a>]]></description><link>background/background-to-retreat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/Background to Retreat.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:35:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="thesis/export/web/media/icons/background.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/background.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-Cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a cloud with a small grin and a big cozy cup of a warm drink of your choice" src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg" target="_self">These inquiries share how the Cozy-Cloud has disobediently made wiggle room to crip server and network infrastructures through the politics of disability justice and life affirmation.These inquiries take the form of solo and collaborative action research and technical practice. These works were presented at Mesh Festival and published in Brand-New-Life journal as well as at a residency at the BDFI.These inquiries aim to question how crip intimacies and critical access can disobediently wiggle room towards life affirming network infrastructures, practices and relations. Here bringing focus to how disabled experiences, embodied knowing and independent practices offer up ample room to disorient the prescribed network configurations towards ones that are shaped by the bodies and embodied expertise they are in touch with.<br>Multi column This entry shares the cozy installation and relaxation space for the Cozy-Cloud. It brings together the soft fluffy cushions, the easy read cozy intentions and the servers tactile base. This entry shares the first theme for the Cozy-Cloud's website. Working with Pico, this light weight and (somewhat) accessible blog hosted the server's original Cozy-Intention. This entry shares the cozy intentions for the cozy-cloud. These intentions both shape thepromise and orientation of this crip network infrastructure, but also offer up how Alt texts and network access practices can make room to imagine this infrastructure through care, joy and creativity. This entry shares the crip infrastructure made in collaboration with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://marianamarangoni.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://marianamarangoni.com/" target="_self">Mariana Marangoni</a> called En-crip-ing Time. This infrastructure crips the Cozy-Cloud server's clock and manifests a poetic chronic job to server up what network intimacies might be liveable through critical access, crip politics and intimate maintenance practices. This entry shares the latest theme for the Cozy-Cloud blog and which focuses on being much more accessible. It both made to be picked up by browser easy readers as well as a more accessible interface for the community to add posts to it. <br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;- Back to Practice</a>]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:50:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/cozy.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-Grid's In-frastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a server grounded through a heart, bringing these often hard systems in touch with soft feelings" src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg" target="_self">These inquiries offer up how critical access can be brought into collaborations within non-disabled centred communities, not as extra time, but as a way to disobediently wiggle room within infrastructures for interdependent sense making and direct action. These inquiries take on the form of focus groups, accessible docs and a set of workshops called Practising Protocols that was run both In-ternally with In-grid as well as at 4S/EASST. These inquiries aim to share how critical access methods and crip theory made room for a collective like In-grid to question our collective organisational and network infrastructures. In this inquiry especially bring focus to how disobedient critical access and disability can make room to not approached as participating in normalised relations or as extra time. Instead crip theory here makes room to disobediently inform our practices through interdependent practice of accessible sense-making and direct action.Multi column This entry shares a collective focus group with In-grid members to reflect on their organisational practices and approaches. In this session questioning how members made sense of and made friction around the social and institutional inflexibilities they came into contact with and were impacted by when organising. This entry reflects on collective action research with In-grid members around how to practice and imagine what technical Docs and network practices have the capacity for when approached through critical access. In these practices questioning how technical configurations and their expertise can make room for being disputed, improvised and manifested from a wide range of backgrounds and approaches. This entry shares a combined panel and workshop organised by In-grid members for 4S/EASST. On the panel disobediently making room for speakers from a range of backgrounds to share their collective practices and approaches around community infrastructuring. With the workshop running the first iteration of the Practising Protocols workshop which made room for collaborators to feel out, find friction with and counter the figures of network configurations. This entry shares a collective workshop where In-grid members came together to run the Practising Protocols workshop in-ternally. For this iteration we set up our first collective server as well as our first server manifesto called the Femfester. In this workshop making room to find friction within our network infrastructures so to manifest them otherwise. <br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;- Back to Practice</a>]]></description><link>in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Grid's In-frastructures.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:40:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/in-configure.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disobedient Access Requests]]></title><description><![CDATA[This disobedient access request came about through a commissioned audio piece for the Tate Modern and their <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.tate.org.uk/story-player/electric-dreams-fm" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.tate.org.uk/story-player/electric-dreams-fm" target="_self">Electric Dreams FM</a>. This radio show and audio piece was an accessible digital selection that was supposed to create an accessible accompaniment to the main in person Electric Dreams exhibition. Through this commission I started an inquiry to feel out the limits of these institutions and the capacities a disobedient access request has to disrupt, disorient and refuse their normalised configurations. <br><img alt="A screen shot from a contract with the Tate displaying a &quot;Note&quot; disclaiming it cannot be shared on platforms run by Google LLC" src="thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png" target="_self">The above images share an access request I made which wiggled room to refuse platforms of Big Tech (Google) with my media. This was only a small gesture but aimed to feel out a promise of how access as a practice can make room to retreat from these normalised and violent institutions. ]]></description><link>configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/disobedient-access-requests.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Disobedient Access Requests.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:26:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/export/web/thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/export/web/thesis/repo/thesis/05_configure-able_methods/05_media/google-excemption.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="The event poster for &quot;Configure-Able Infrastructures&quot;. It has a blurry background of greens, reds and blues. On top are a number of boxes outlined and linked by white dashed lines and filed with white text. The top box has the title of the event, and then connects to others, one holding &quot;A set of workshops/talks creating dialogues around what configure-able infra can be&quot;, another stating &quot;Melt, 19th July, Access sparks: incendiary emails for change making&quot; and another with &quot;Syster Server 2nd Aug, Organizing the anarcha feminist cyborg hacker uprising&quot;" src="configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" target="_self"><br>These collaborative workshops were organised with NEoN digital to make room to explore queer, feminist and crip methods towards network infrastructures. In these workshops I collaborated with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://meltionary.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://meltionary.com/" target="_self">MELT</a> and members of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://systerserver.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://systerserver.net/" target="_self">SysterServer</a> to run two workshops and share how collective access can be understood and actioned within digital networks.Due to a desire to run these workshops online and through Free Libre Open Source Softwar (FLOSS) these workshops also offered up a number of frictions around how FLOSS imagines and makes space for accessibility. This came from the realisation that in the context of this workshop where we needed automated captions, there were no easily accessible FLOSS softwares that could meet these requirements. From this friction we not only emerged an understanding of how FLOSS does not make room for accessibility, nor does it imagine it as essential. From this friction the workshop also made room to improvise and hack together an automated live captioning setup that both made room for everyone to meet through FLOSS online, but also for people to setup their own local live captioning software on their computer if they wanted it. This improvised setup even though being on individuals computers was also felt out and shared through interdependence and collective sense making. This entry shares the event page for the workshop. This holds more information on who was there, what they presented and more details on the event. This entry shares the improvised auto-captioning software that we hacked together for the workshop so that we could try to make FLOSS video calls accessible.
]]></description><link>configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/configure-able-infrastructures-workshop.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Configure-Able Infrastructures Workshop.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 19:03:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/02_configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/02_configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Improvised Captions]]></title><description><![CDATA[This page shares the improvised automated caption setup that was made and shared for the <a data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures" href="configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Configure-Able Infrastructures</a> workshops. Alongside this is also shared here how the different FLOSS video call and automated caption software we tried and that lacked the capacities that was needed for the workshop.It does have to be said that even with this desire to manifest FLOSS access, the improvised automated captions we came up with still ended up working with big tech solutions. In discussion we felt working here with google's local automated caption on a FLOSS video call was a way to wiggle room towards access within FLOSS. Even though this approach also did ask individuals to configure their own access, we tried to offer up interdependent access through clear instructions, as well as being their to debug issues. This need for configuration though was also felt to be a place to be in contact with and feel out automated captioning software. If you need to use Live Caption here are steps to run them locally on Chrome. This needs you to download the browser, join the Live Caption is only available in English. On your computer, download and open Chrome.
At the top right, click More&nbsp;Settings.
At the bottom of the Settings page, click&nbsp;Accessibility.
Turn on&nbsp;Live Caption. Tips:&nbsp; When you play a video, to turn on captions, at the top right click Media control.
To use Live Captions for videos that auto-play, turn on the video volume.
When you click away from the tab with sound, live captions will appear in a hover-bubble that you can drag. To return to the tab with audio, click. Here I share the frictions we found with FLOSS video calls when trying to find accessible platforms and ways of meeting through them. This did have a way of doing live captions, but needed you to set it up from the backend and host Jitsi yourself to do this. We both did not host a Jitsi instance, nor could find one that had this already installed.
After the first workshop, we also realised that Jitsi can only host a small group of people, and the workshop size meant people could not alwas access the session. <br>This had room for <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="%5Bhttps://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions%5D(https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="[https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions](https://support.bigbluebutton.org/hc/en-us/articles/1500005215861-Use-Closed-Captions)" target="_self">live captioning</a> (which is great!), but for a workshop like this that lacked the funds to hire a live-captioner, there was no automated option. Here is a list of addons for Firefox that were also tested out and did not quite work or were not accessible. <br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/auto-subtitle/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/auto-subtitle/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/ideas/live-captioning/idi-p/7548" target="_self">https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/ideas/live-captioning/idi-p/7548</a>&nbsp;
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/add-subtitles/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/add-subtitles/</a>&nbsp;
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/substital/" target="_self">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/substital/</a>
]]></description><link>configure-able/configure-able-infra-workshop/improvised-captions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-able Infra Workshop/Improvised Captions.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:28:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able Infrastructures]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A minimal icon illustrates an institution wiggling and all of its supports at angles to their normalized straight orientation" src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg" target="_self">
These inquiries offer up how critical access knowledge disobediently makes [Glossary#^93ca91|Wiggle Room]] to disorient the prescribed configurations of infrastructures through the expertise of the bodies they impact. These inquiries focus in specifically on how the frictions of access making and requesting offer up room to make sense of the limits and capacities of institutes and their infrastructures. In this room disobediently bringing in to focus how counter imaginaries and actions can be contoured from this feeling of friction, and directly actioned into friction making. Multi column This entry reflects on the running of the Configure-Able Infrastructures workshops at NEoN Digital which shared practices around crip and feminist networks. Organising this accessible workshop through Free Libra Open Source Software (FLOSS) offered up frictions and room here doe collaborators to critique the normalised configurations and ableist assumptions of FLOSS. At the same time it also shares how from these frictions collaborators improvise crip infrastructures for automated captions then and there. This entry shares the how access requesting to institutions, such as the Tate, can be a site of hacking and disorienting configurations through the political and relational direct actions of crip informed critical access. This is where the practice of disobedient access requesting aims to build up the relational capacity to reconfigure infrastructures and disrupt their normalised dependencies. <br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;- Back to Practice</a>]]></description><link>configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/Configure-Able Infrastructures.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:12:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="thesis/export/web/media/icons/configure-able.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Practice]]></title><description><![CDATA[This page shares the practice, inquiries and research this project took towards manifesting Configure-able Infrastructures informed through critical access and crip practices. These different <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^d188f3" data-href="Glossary#^d188f3" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cripped Tables</a> of inquiries emerged through my <a class="internal-link" data-href="Methods.md" href="methods.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Disobedient Action Research Methods</a> and are split into two sections, called Inquiries and Background. These aim to offer up together the foreground of the main inquiries as well as the background to this research that they are contoured from.This section shares the main inquiries, practice and collaborative research into manifesting Configure-able Infrastructures in action. These inquiries take on the form of workshops, focus groups, technical docs, speculative infrastructures and * * * * *. These are split into three sections which each ask their own unique questions around how critical access and crip theory can disorient the normalising relations of configurations to instead shape infrastructures around the bodies they impact.<br>Multi column <a class="internal-link" data-href="Configure-Able Infrastructures.md" href="configure-able/configure-able-infrastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"><span alt="A minimal icon illustrates an institution wiggling and all of its straight supports at angles to their normalized orientation" src="media/icons/configure-able.svg" class="internal-embed media-embed image-embed is-loaded" target="_self"></span></a><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates an institution wiggling and all of its straight supports at angles to their normalized orientation" src="media/icons/configure-able.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries offer up how critical access knowledge disobediently makes <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> for the prescribed configurations of infrastructures to be disoriented, hacked and reconfigured through the expertise and access knowledges of the bodies they impact. <a class="internal-link" data-href="In-Grid's In-frastructures.md" href="in-grid/in-grid's-in-frastructures.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"><span alt="A minimal icon illustrates a server grounded through a heart, bringing these often hard systems in touch with soft feelings" src="media/icons/in-configure.svg" class="internal-embed media-embed image-embed is-loaded" target="_self"></span></a><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a server grounded through a heart, bringing these often hard systems in touch with soft feelings" src="media/icons/in-configure.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries offer up how critical access can be brought into collaborations within non-disability communities, not as extra time, but as a way to disobediently <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> within infrastructures to make accessible practices of interdependent sense making and direct action. <a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"><span alt="A minimal icon illustrates a cloud with a small grin and a big cozy cup of a hot drink of your choice" src="media/icons/cozy.svg" class="internal-embed media-embed image-embed is-loaded" target="_self"></span></a><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a cloud with a small grin and a big cozy cup of a hot drink of your choice" src="media/icons/cozy.svg" target="_self"><br>
These inquiries share how the Cozy-Cloud has disobediently made <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> to crip server and network infrastructures through unfolding practices of access making and life affirmation. <br>This section shares more of the background to the research. This is predominantly to make known what this work is in retreat from, but also what research practices have shaped these inquiries. These reflections are here to disobediently situate this work and make <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> to balance what is in focus, with what it has unfolded from.<br>Multi column <a class="internal-link" data-href="Background to Retreat.md" href="background/background-to-retreat.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"><span alt="A minimal icon illustrates a picture frame hanging from a thread. There is no canvas in the frame making room for a scene to be set." src="media/icons/background.svg" class="internal-embed media-embed image-embed is-loaded" target="_self"></span></a><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a picture frame hanging from a thread. There is no canvas in the frame making room for a scene to be set." src="media/icons/background.svg" target="_self"><br>
These background inquiries share the sense making of configurations of automation, AI and decision making. Here disobediently making <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> to share what this research is turning away from. <a class="internal-link" data-href="Research Practice.md" href="research/research-practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"><span alt="A minimal icon illustrates a set of points connected into a network. This cluster of connected points emerging into a form of their own." src="media/icons/knowledge-graph.svg" class="internal-embed media-embed image-embed is-loaded" target="_self"></span></a><img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a set of points connected into a network. This cluster of connected points emerging into a form of their own." src="media/icons/knowledge-graph.svg" target="_self">
This section shares the research practices that have made room for these inquiries to unfold. In it I bring focus to a workshop I ran with Batool Desouky called Making Sense With Obsidian, in which we shared our approach to gathering and bringing together our research and inquiries. ]]></description><link>practice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Practice.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:47:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/icons/configure-able.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/icons/configure-able.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crip Disobedient Action Research Methods]]></title><description><![CDATA[ The indeterminate diagram above is representative of how this project's disobedient methodology disorients the standardized and prescribed methods of configuration. Every time you visit this page, and every time you click on the diagram, it creates a different composition of actions, sense makings and wiggling of room that my methodology entices. Visually it forms loops and cycles of different network diagram symbols and labels connected by lines and arrows. Each diagram also has a generated alt text of the syntax of the diagram which can be interpreted in a similarly playful way, and is attached to the &lt;div&gt; with the .mermaid class. Here are the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://mermaid.js.org/syntax/flowchart.html" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://mermaid.js.org/syntax/flowchart.html" target="_self">mermaid docs</a> to help decode diagrams.
This code is an edit of another work/performance called <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/georgie-png/Pad2Party" target="_self">Pad2Party</a> that Sunni Liao and I made as part or <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.in-grid.io/projects/real-bodies-2.1/" target="_self">RealBodies 2.1</a> with In-grid.
The methodology for this project is a Disobedient Action Research Methodology. As the above texture and indeterminate diagram tries to highlight, this methodology disobediently refuses to be generalized or normalized into set terms of engagement. Instead this projects methodology aims to make wiggle room for bringing in the backgrounds of the bodyminds to be in touch with and shape the sociotechnical infrastructures and matters they are impacted by. To build up my projects Disobedient Action Research methodology I crip the methods of TiTIPi to ask what room can collective embodied inquiries make within infrastructuring. With this methodology disobediently being intimate with and building up collective expertise around what is and can be within reach socially and technically. In this Disobedient methodology I also aims to re-frame what actions can be taken within my research and how they can coalesce together and shape what is made known through action within the often hard and inflexible configurations of complex systems.The disobedience ]]></description><link>methods.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Methods.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 08:38:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is It Configure-Able?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="layers" src="site-lib/media/favicon.svg" target="_self"><br>This project aims to make room to inquire into manifesting Configure-Able Infrastructures. Informed by Queer theory, crip theory and critical access practices, Configure-able Infrastructures orients from their sites of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^d9bca1" data-href="Glossary#^d9bca1" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Friction</a>. From <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^d9bca1" data-href="Glossary#^d9bca1" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Friction</a> moving to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> around how these processes and relations can be shaped by and for the bodies they impact.<br>Orienting with Sarah Ahmed's <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^85fb82" data-href="Glossary#^85fb82" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Table</a> (2006), I make room to question how the institutional norms of computing and academia keep the life affirming infrastructures collaborators and I desire out of reach of my <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^6a7cf2" data-href="Glossary#^6a7cf2" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bodily Horizon</a>. With Ahmed and Helen Pritchard's concept of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^93ca91" data-href="Glossary#^93ca91" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wiggle Room</a> (2022; 2014) I question how to make room to feel these pains and misfitting of the table, and in response wiggle, disorient and shape these <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary > ^d188f3" data-href="Glossary#^d188f3" href="thesis/repo/practice/glossary.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cripped Tables</a> by and for disabled expertise, futures and wisdom. With Alison Kafer (2013) and Aimi Hamraie (2017), I surface the ways they begin to not only validate the feelings and sense making of friction within relations, but also the making of friction from embodied expertise and through interdependent action. add a bit more info
add an about page?
]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/index.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:34:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/export/web/site-lib/media/favicon.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/export/web/site-lib/media/favicon.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Research Practice]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A minimal icon illustrates a set of points connected into a network. This cluster of connected points emerging into a form of their own." src="research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png" target="_self">This section highlights some of the knowledge base practice and research which is not that present on this research table but helped to bring it into being. This work is orienting that of how I collected, collated and held together this research through notes, short essays, annotated essays, chapters and media. To do this I worked with Obsidian as it made room for me to hold these many disparate things together. To do this here I share the workshop Making Sense with Obsidian that me and Batool Desouky organised for students on the Make Sense program at the Critical Media Lab, FNHW, Basel. This workshop aimed to share the practices Batool and I had emerged within Obsidian, but in a way that makes room for others to hack and emerge their own approach to researching. Check out the:
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/sunSeekingGoth/MakeSenseWithObsidian" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/sunSeekingGoth/MakeSenseWithObsidian" target="_self">Workshop materials</a>
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="../Practice.md" href="practice.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">&lt;- Back to Practice</a>]]></description><link>research/research-practice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Research/Research Practice.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:00:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/05_research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/05_research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving Cozy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="In among a cluster of Cozy-Cloud pillows, the small server's screen illuminates a hand reaching towards it. The screen they are reaching towards has written on it &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;." src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png" target="_self"><br>This is the installed Cozy-Cloud relaxation space and server that makes room for disabled bodies to be in proximity to network infrastructure and for them to make their own knowing and expertise of them through multi-sensory and media approaches. This server is hosted using a VPN so that it can move around and bring with it this relaxation space to imagine crip networks infrastructures from. To make this cozy relaxation space this server brings with it cozy cloud cushions, stickers and a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Thesis/export/static/Thesis/Repo/08_Practice/08_Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/Cozy Intentions Easy Read.pdf" data-href="Thesis/export/static/Thesis/Repo/08_Practice/08_Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/Cozy Intentions Easy Read.pdf" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Printable Easy Read Version</a> of the <a data-href="Cozy-Intentions" href="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Intentions</a>. This aims to offer up room around the Cozy-Cloud server, and outside of network space to emerge, and specifically from relaxing, dream full and cozy backgrounds and contexts.<br><img alt="An Inviting pile of Cozy-Cloud Pillows with the server snuggled up in the middle. The cloud pillows being extra fluffy and making room for cozy crip network imaginaries." src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg" target="_self"><br><img alt="A close up of the Cozy-Cloud server sitting within the cloud pillows with its background sharing the words &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;. The server sits on top a custom made base with a cloud engraved in it and the words &quot;let's get cozy&quot; cut into it." src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.jpeg" target="_self"><br><img alt="A diagram of the installed artworks flow. Most important here is sharing that people do not have to connect to the internet or the server to engage in the work and just have room to relax if they want. It also shares the other points of entry from the easy read through to the online blog." src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/cozy-flow.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="An SVG file I used to engrave and cut out the base for the server. It is a cloud with multiple layers and lines to add a tactile description of this form. Around the edges in cluncky placment are the words &quot;Let's-Get-Cozy&quot; outlined to be cut out. In the middle are four red circles for the server to be attached to it." src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.svg" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/serving-cozy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/Serving Cozy.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[En-crip-ing_time]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A cover image by Mariana for Mesh festival. This is in grey scale and has a glitchy background of a distorted noisy image with random numbers, letters and symbols in lines across it. On top on this in clear black writing on a white background are the words &quot;En-crip-in Time&quot;." src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" target="_self"><br>This is a crip infrastructure I made in collaboration with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://marianamarangoni.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://marianamarangoni.com/" target="_self">Mariana Marangoni</a> that inquired how we could make room for crip time in network time, now and in the future. It also questions the intimacies and care needed to not only manifest, but maintain crip infrastructures like these. This work was presented at Mesh Festival, as well as an essay about it published with Brand-New-Life Journal.Check out the:
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://time.cozy-cloud.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://time.cozy-cloud.net/" target="_self">Crip infrastructure live</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://brand-new-life.org/b-n-l/en-crip-ing-time/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://brand-new-life.org/b-n-l/en-crip-ing-time/" target="_self">Published essay</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://2024.meshfestival.ch/events/george-simms-mariana-marangoni-chronic-qts/de.html" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://2024.meshfestival.ch/events/george-simms-mariana-marangoni-chronic-qts/de.html" target="_self">Mesh festival talk info</a>
<br><img alt="A snapshot of the live infrastructure and poem with the CSS working, as it will be different every time it is visited. The screen is filled with a mixture of fonts and placements in green, which hold different lines of the crip time poem. Here you can read lines like &quot;A home for us together&quot;, &quot;Of frictionless desire&quot;, as well as others. Their are bright pink almost unreadable bits of text which highlight the en-crip-ed lines of the poem." src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="A web browser with the poem and its code showing side by side. Here I am sharing how in-between the the lines of the code/poem their are comments reflecting on the crip times of care that made this infrastructure possible." src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/en-crip-ing_time.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/En-crip-ing_time/En-crip-ing_time.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy_Night_and_Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="An image sharing the day layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme has a gradient background, going from warm yellow at the bottom to off white at the top. on the left if the title of the site saying &quot;Cozy-Cloud&quot; in a bold font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is a Cozy-Cloud resting appearing cozy and welcoming." src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" target="_self"><br>This is the current website theme for the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Cloud.md" href="cozy-cloud/cozy-cloud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Cloud</a>, and works with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.bludit.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.bludit.com/" target="_self">Bludit CMS</a>. It is made to have be very light weight and network accessible, as it also utilises tags/code to activate Screen Readers (shared below). This website so far documents the work of the Cozy-Cloud by giving lightweight introductions to each work. It also aims to be a step towards making more room within this infrastructure for easier collaborations and exchanges as it can have multiple users and work in the web interface. Check out the:
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/georgie-png/cozy_night-day" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/georgie-png/cozy_night-day" target="_self">Downloadable Theme</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://cozy-cloud.net/cozy-pagesss" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cozy-cloud.net/cozy-pagesss" target="_self">Instructions on how to run it</a>
Formatting your html or php so it uses these tags will enable screen readers to easily pick up on the content in a page.&lt;article&gt; &lt;h2 class="mb2"&gt; page title &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; by &lt;span class="author"&gt;author&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;time class="dateline"&gt;date&lt;/time&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cover"&gt;&lt;img src="./cover.img" alt="a cute cover image"/&gt;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Content &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
<br><img alt="An image sharing the day layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme has a gradient background, going from warm yellow at the bottom to off white at the top. on the left if the title of the site saying &quot;Cozy-Cloud&quot; in a bold black font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is a Cozy-Cloud resting appearing cozy and welcoming." src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="An image sharing the night layout of the Cozy night+day theme. This theme has a gradient background, going from bark red/purple at the bottom to warm red at the top. Nn the left if the title of the site saying &quot;Cozy-Cloud&quot; in a bold white font, and a list of categories and their pages below. On the bottom right is a Cozy-Cloud resting appearing cozy and welcoming." src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="An image sharing how the website activates and can be accessed with a screen reader. This is the default Firefox screen reader and shares the page en-crip-ing time page with the access menu on the left, letting people adapt how they can access this information" src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/cozy_night_and_day.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy_Night+Day/Cozy_Night_and_Day.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-ish]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="A screen shot of the Cozy-ish Theme, which has a orange to yellow gradient att the bottom which gently fade to off white at the top. The theme has a funky title font in the top right, a clear simple menu on the left with an arrow point to the current file. The page content is held in the midle and scrolls out of a fade from the bottom." src="cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" target="_self"><br>Cozy-ish is the first theme for the Cozy-Cloud blog which ran with a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://picocms.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://picocms.org/" target="_self">Pico CMS</a>. This theme was initially made to hold the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Cozy-Intentions.md" href="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-Intentions</a> as well as some docs for the early setup. It is made to be an accessible, minimal and Cozy aesthetic to host these intentions and information. It is an adapted version of Winnie Soon's <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://gitlab.com/siusoon/soonish/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://gitlab.com/siusoon/soonish/" target="_self"><em></em></a>Soonish and adds a few minor edits to make it a lil more cozy.Check out the:
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-ish/media/Cozy-ish_theme.zip" href="cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/cozy-ish_theme.zip" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cozy-ish_theme.zip</a> (download theme)
]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/cozy-ish.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-ish/Cozy-ish.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy-Intentions]]></title><description><![CDATA[This page brings together cozy intentions for the cozy-cloud crip (disability justice) space. This is to give an understanding of how * why this crip centred platform came to be and to share some of the desires we have when making an affirmative digital space that centres disabled people.These intentions appear as image and alt text pairs, each defining its own thread to be followed, weaving together a story or figuring of the cozy-cloud. In a classic crip move, they entangle together the affective feelings of our mind body and their knowledges, within an understanding of political relational modelling to imagine new ways to transform our social * technical infrastructures.&nbsp;Simply put these intentions mean to affirm what we feel as disabled people in both our bodies and minds, and to enable those knowledges at the centre of transforming digital communication networks and systems like social media platforms. maybe something about enviro x materialThese intentions ask: If we as disabled neurodiverse chronically ill people are able to transform digital spaces and communities and their material infrastructure (+ the environmental effects they have) from a space of crip care and time, what could that look like and feel like?If you are a member of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://care.cozy-cloud.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://care.cozy-cloud.net/" target="_self">cozy-cloud</a> platform and want to add to or tweak these intentions and you have not had the opportunity yet please message <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://care.cozy-cloud.net/u/COZY" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://care.cozy-cloud.net/u/COZY" target="_self">COZY</a> for the etherpad they are edited on.<br><img alt="Furry text saying &quot;Let's Get Cozy&quot;, welcomes you to get cozy! This is an enthusiastic and loving message reminding you to get cozy in what ever way you are able to. Many times (not always) when we can't get cozy,our experience it is telling us that something might be wrong systemically. This text asks us to think, what would enable me to get cozy? What relations would have to change for us to actually be cozy? By trying to get cozy we start to make these transformations, so settle in and lets get cozy." src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" target="_self">Furry text saying "Let's Get Cozy", welcomes you to get cozy! This is an enthusiastic and loving message reminding you to get cozy in what ever way you are able to.Many times (not always) when we can't get cozy,our experience it is telling us that something might be wrong systemically. This text asks us to think, what would enable me to get cozy? What relations would have to change for us to actually be cozy? By trying to get cozy we start to make these transformations, so settle in and lets get cozy.<br><img alt="A cloud sits unsure on a day with mixed weather. It feels sensitive to the gusts and gales of bigger clouds and so searches for a sheltered valley to get cozy and come back to earth. It asks us to think about how we feel in the cloud. When we are using cloud enabled devices, like streaming, cloud drives or social platforms do we feel a connection to what it is we are doing? What would it feel like to ground and get cozy with our digital infrastructures." src="my-projects-🗃/cozy-cloud/previs/imgs/cloud5.png" target="_self">A cloud sits unsure on a day with mixed weather. It feels sensitive to the gusts and gales of bigger clouds and so searches for a sheltered valley to get cozy and come back to earth. It asks us to think about how we feel in the cloud. When we are using cloud enabled devices, like streaming, cloud drives or social platforms do we feel a connection to what it is we are doing? What would it feel like to ground and get cozy with our digital infrastructures.<br><img alt="The cozy-cloud sits within a ring of furry and cozy text saying &quot;Less Cloud - More Cozy&quot;. It feels warmth in knowing its energies are conserved for doing cozy things and not being a part of deadly storms elsewhere. It asks us to think about less dispersion of our digital selves into a commercial cloud that displaces the harms of digital infrastructures out of sight. How can we settle in, keep ourselves close and feel out how cozy our clouds could be?" src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.png" target="_self">The cozy-cloud sits within a ring of furry and cozy text saying "Less Cloud - More Cozy". It feels warmth in knowing its energies are conserved for doing cozy things and not being a part of deadly storms elsewhere. It asks us to think about less dispersion of our digital selves into a commercial cloud that displaces the harms of digital infrastructures out of sight. How can we settle in, keep ourselves close and feel out how cozy our clouds could be?<br><img alt="Slightly clumsy but cute furry text says &quot;Clouds are finite :( Coziness can be infinite!&quot;. It sits slightly slumped to one side, exhausted with keeping up with the continuous expansion. It helps us to reflect on the limitations of computing and cloud infrastructures, the consumption of fossil fuels, rare minerals and people's labour to try to maintain the unmaintainable infinite growth. What if we centre our clouds on other infinities of care, compassion and coziness? What would infrastructures feel like and be able of through these gentler modes?" src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.png" target="_self">Slightly clumsy but cute furry text says "Clouds are finite :( Coziness can be infinite!". It sits slightly slumped to one side, exhausted with keeping up with the continuous expansion. It helps us to reflect on the limitations of computing and cloud infrastructures, the consumption of fossil fuels, rare minerals and people's labour to try to maintain the unmaintainable infinite growth. What if we centre our clouds on other infinities of care, compassion and coziness? What would infrastructures feel like and be able of through these gentler modes?<br><img alt="A map of arpnet, an early computer network produced by the us gov/army is transformed into a cozy-constellation. This transformation resembles the way digital networks have a history of control of space (both physical and virtual) through force and how we have to transform them with care and coziness. It asks us how we could imagine networks away from these histories of mapping, taxonomy and creating specific ways of knowing/doing? Instead can we imagine it as a relation of gravitates to be felt but unknowable?" src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png" target="_self">A map of arpnet, an early computer network produced by the us gov/army is transformed into a cozy-constellation. This transformation resembles the way digital networks have a history of control of space (both physical and virtual) through force and how we have to transform them with care and coziness.It asks us how we could imagine networks away from these histories of mapping, taxonomy and creating specific ways of knowing/doing? Instead can we imagine it as a relation of gravitates to be felt but unknowable? <br><img alt="A png of a cloud with transparent background so that it looks like it is comfortable and confident wherever it is displayed. The cloud looks so light and pretty floating on the page, but still on the edge of creating a little drizzle. The image itself is also on a free license so is free like a cloud! It reminds us what a cloud looks like and what it is able of. The computational infrastructures that make up the commercial cloud could never be so light nor caring to our ecology nor our body/minds. What metaphors or analogies would you give the cloud? How would you transform them through putting this digital infrastructure in your own terms." src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.png" target="_self">A png of a cloud with transparent background so that it looks like it is comfortable and confident wherever it is displayed. The cloud looks so light and pretty floating on the page, but still on the edge of creating a little drizzle. The image itself is also on a free license so is free like a cloud!It reminds us what a cloud looks like and what it is able of. The computational infrastructures that make up the commercial cloud could never be so light nor caring to our ecology nor our body/minds. What metaphors or analogies would you give the cloud? How would you transform them through putting this digital infrastructure in your own terms.]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/Cozy-Intentions.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving In-grid Workshop slides]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this workshop I aim for us to think about how we make and imagine collective places of infrastructure. In this exchange we will materially and technically setup a server space, and along that journey together we will ask questions and discuss&nbsp;how we want to practice these technologies collectively.The end goal is to have collectively edited set of protocols or a manifesto that we publish to an html page on the server.Material for this workshop was developed from collaborative work over a number of iterations from projects including servpub, collective infrastructures and cozy-cloud.Outcomes from this workshop will also be used in my PhD as well as published in the new Servus journal? (I think it is) And I will make sure we are all credited!This workshop and the server are hosted by Servus in Linx Austria. They are an artist run data centre and have given us this space to practice our own network tech and projects. It is run on hydro electric energy and hosts a number of other collectives, tech enthusiasts and artists.We will be making and editing a manifesto of sorts as we work through the steps of this workshop. These will be hosted on an html file on the server, and is accessible at this URL page: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io/" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io/</a><br>Until then we will edit them on this pad: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://digitalcare.noho.st/pad/p/Femfester" target="_self">https://digitalcare.noho.st/pad/p/Femfester</a>
p.s. Femfester can be changed.
When it comes to making collaborative community driven sociotechnical infrastructure, there is always a complex network of relations that we have to work through. Negotiating every relation when we enter a space could be very complex and time consuming, as we will see, but setting protocols helps us firm up ways of working and relational conventions that ease this flow. Through setting these protocols together we mean to disobey the norms of network infrastructures and actively re-scope how we come to these systems and relations together.<br><img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" target="_self"><br>Relating to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" target="_self">original feminist server manifesto</a> by some of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://constantvzw.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://constantvzw.org/" target="_self">Constant</a>. Manifesting and imagining what a feminist server is and does.A feminist server…&nbsp; * Is a situated technology. She has a sense of context and considers herself to be part of an ecology of practices
* Is run for and by a community that cares enough for h
er in order to make her exist
* Builds on the materiality of software, hardware and the bodies gathered around it
* Opens herself to expose processes, tools, sources, habits, patterns
* Does not strive for seamlessness. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible
* Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be traps
* Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous and parasitic practice
* Is autonomous in the sense that she decides for her own dependencies
* Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; experiments with changing client-server relations where she can
* Treats network technology as part of a social reality
* Wants networks to be mutable and read-write accessible
* Does not confuse safety with security
* Takes the risk of exposing her insecurity
* Tries hard not to apologize when she is sometimes not available
Manifesto = Man x Infest
Infest being the taking hold of and grasping threateningly at things as proof! Femfester = Feminism x Fistula
Fistula being part of an festering, a pipeline with many holes. Thinking of a patchwork infra!
We can change this, it was just me having fun with wordz.<br>You can have a lot of passwords and bits here, so I use a password manager like <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://keepassxc.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://keepassxc.org/" target="_self">Keypassxc</a>Lets give a little context of working with computers.So most people are probably used to working through a graphical user interface (GUI), which is a relatively recent way of interfacing with a computer. This is great for accessibility but also tends to scope and direct the abilities and capacities you have on your computer, as in there are only so many buttons or things you can show in a communicable way. “Thesis 📖/workshops/serv(er)ing in-grid/media/howdyTerminal.png” could not be found.Terminal is a more classic way of working with a machine, and roughly speaking is the step between punch-card/magnetic tape style computing and a GUI. It is a very simple but powerful interface that lets you run basically any command on your system through a text interface. Compared to a GUI this space is more "risky" as you can do anything from anywhere, such as deleting the entire operating system (not advised). It also means that there are no limitations to your system administration so you have access to a granular level of working. Prompt
When entering into this more "risky" space on a computer network, it is good to set some intentions and work out how to move through this space with care. As we go though these next steps getting into terminal have a think about what it means to be in this place of power/risk, and what relations you think you need to care for in the formation of these protocols?
It can also be a great place to think about if/how the relations of a system enables you to perform this role of power, and what change in relations this new role brings with it. This depends on your platform, so...On a Mac it is already installed! So all you need to do is:
Search up Terminal
Open it!
There are similar programs to terminal already installed, but not the same language (bash). There are a few ways to do this, but I recomend installing an ubuntu vm shell for bash, as it gives the most capability for this use case:
<br>Install the VM from the windows store <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9PDXGNCFSCZV?ocid=pdpshare" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9PDXGNCFSCZV?ocid=pdpshare" target="_self">HERE</a>and remember your password!
Then open it up!
As we said before terminal is a text/syntax-based way of interfacing your machine and we are going to introduce a few basic commands and concepts to get us going today.Let's simply use echo to get our terminal to say HI!.To do this use:echo &lt;message&gt;
e.g.echo HI!
Now lets see who your computer!Show the name of the currently logged in user:whoami
Show the name of the machine is given on the network:hostname
Much of working on the command line involves navigating around your system without the use of a Graphical User Interface (GUI).However, we will essentially be navigating around normal computer folder hierarchies like below:root/
├─ directoryname/ ├─ anotherdirectory/ ├─ aFileName.txt
Directory&nbsp;: also known as a folderPrint working directory that you are currently in:pwd
List current directory contents:ls
Now to move between directories/folders we use cd like socd &lt;directory_name&gt;
e.g.cd folder1 We can use a folder that was shown with ls in the last step!
You can also check whats in the new folder with ls to see that you have moved.
Prompt
In this potentially unfamiliar space how do we keep track of where we are, what we've done &amp; what commands we may need in the future?
Basically how do we want to orient ourselves?
Secure Shell (SSH) is a way of working on another machine from your own, working in their shell (bash). It basically lets you work on another computers terminal remotely. This is the way you will work on most servers or remote/faceless computers (computers without a screen).<br><img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/sshdiagram.jpg" target="_self">The SSH protocol enables us to talk securely to our server by encrypting and authenticating all of our communication/interfacing through the network. Traditionally tech has a metaphor of SSH as a secure hand shake protocol, but it will be great to think about what metaphor or relation we want when it comes to crossing boundaries and into shared spaces. Do we want to hand shake or do we think . . . would enable . . . Again this may be a bit different on different systems, as some will have this already installed and some will need to install it. Install it with:sudo apt install openssh-client
If you are on gitbash on windows, it should be installed.To SSH into the Server with servus we need to use their IP!An IP address is basically the postcode/address we will find the pi at on the network.The IP for our Servus server is:
193.170.194.204But we also have it as a named server:
vps.in-grid.ioNow that we have the IP address, any computer can request to SSH into the server through these commands:ssh &lt;user_name&gt;@&lt;ip&gt;
eg.ssh in-grid@193.170.194.204
orssh in-grid@vps.in-grid.io
You are now "logging into" our server, so it will ask for the password here and that I will share with you.You should now see your terminal username change from your laptop's local user to something like: in-grid@vps:~$ If you want to exit out of the pi (we don't atm) type:exit
Hit enter. You will need to have exited the pi before setting up your ssh key. Prompt
How do we navigate another machine through our own "interface"?
What are the relational agreements to being on this other machine?
Sudo enables us to take on a superuser role.
This means that we have all the security permissions for that system. This is a "very risky" role, as here you can do anything on the server/computer. With sudo you can actually delete the entire system or make other similar drastic commands, but it also means that we have the ability to manage and configure our system to our needs.When we come to writing protocols for sudo, what does it mean for us to be a "superuser" or an admin, and what care and consideration should we take on in these protocols?<br><img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg" target="_self">To become sudo or root you just need to:sudo su
And then enter the password when prompted.Prompt
Super User can Do! a lot... what permissions are we comfortable navigating?
How intimate are we with our machines?
Caring for a server includes routine tasks like updating/upgrading the system software, tiding up files, creating new users &amp; giving access permissions, paying attention to errors and bug reports.We are going to initiate this server by making us all users!<br><img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg" target="_self">To make a new user, use the command below. Note, that you will be prompted to input a password and it is always better to give different users passwordsadduser &lt;nameofuser&gt;
If you want to give this user sudo access, then they have to be added to the "sudo" group. You don't need to create this group, it exists by default and you can just add or remove users from it. The sudo group is stored in this directory: /etc/sudoers.d/usermod -aG sudo &lt;nameofuser&gt;
You can check to see who is in the group sudo using this command: grep '^sudo:.*$' /etc/group
Now you can change into the new user (in other words, sign into their account):su &lt;nameofuser&gt;
You could also log in now with:ssh &lt;username&gt;@193.170.194.204
orssh &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
And log in with the password you just added.Prompt
How can we re-imagine users to something less explicit and more gentle?
How do we want to configure the imaginaries to these roles?
SSH Keys are user specific and are used in addition to a shared login password. To make this method of access truly secure we will need to eventually disable password-only login. The shared password is the Lock, and the private password is the Key. Keys are non-transferable and have to be generated per user. Make sure you are back on your own system with:exit
Then to generate the keys, call this command: ssh-keygen -t rsa
Fill in the information requested (note: most of it is optional so you can leave it blank) and set a password (not optional).The shared key is the:id_rsa.puband the private Key is the:id_rsa Make note of the path to your id_rsa.pub, we'll need it in the next step.The public, Lock, password now needs to be copied over to the raspberry pi. Do this via this command (replacing the first bracket with the path to the id_rsa.pub, and the second to the Pis IP address, which we found earlier):ssh-copy-id -i &lt;path to id_rsa.pub&gt; &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
Enter password to complete transfer.I find it easiest to login with the key linked directly.sudo ssh -i &lt;path/to/id_rsa.pub&gt; &lt;username&gt;@vps.in-grid.io
Note
Maybe check you can become sudo with sudo su
Only do this after everyone who need to access the server has uploaded their Keys!It is also recommended that you keep one person ssh'd in at all times during testing this, so if you do something wrong you can unlock it again.Access the config file by:sudo nano -l /etc/ssh/sshd_config
And in uncomment 'PasswordAuthentication' on line 57 and set to 'no', then save and exit:PasswordAuthentication no
Then restart the SSH connection:sudo service ssh restart
Keep someone logged in at all times!Have someone else log out and back in, trying with a password which should fail, and then the key which should work!Prompt
Now this server is "safe" and secure, can we reflect on what that means to us?
How do we imagine this server being a safe space beyond SSH keys?
Tmux is what is called a multiplexer, which is a software that lets us collectively work one terminal session. This is how many collectives and collaborative networks work together on servers in one space. It lets us edit and run commands in one space and take responsibility and practice our infra becoming together.When we come to writing protocols we might want to think about what it means to be one user together, and how can we keep everyone at the same pace and comfortable levels of understanding. All become sudo with:sudo su
Now we are all sudo we can initiate a shared session to work in together.To do this we use:tmux new -s &lt;session name&gt;
e.g. tmux new -s in-sesh
Now we need to name our collective space. If we think back*forward in this workshop, what are the intentions, dynamics and relations we want to collectively name this space with?Now we have an active session we can join it by just typing:tmux a -t in-sesh Rember we have to be sudo to join this!
Now we can say hi to one another and say cute messages in the space by:echo &lt;message&gt;
Say something to welcome each other into this session, you may need to take turns.As we saw even each of us writing an echo command takes a little bit of choreographing. When this gets more complicated, like writing complex configuration files, you can imagine it gets even more tricky.Prompt
So here we need to think about how we might manage collective editing. What operational metaphor might we use to describe the relationship between the person typing and the others? Who and how do we choose to type? How do we take care of every voice in that conversation?
We've created a simple html document to edit. We need to navigate to that file, open and edit it. First lets navigate to the folder its inside and list its contents.cd /var/www/femfester
ls
We should see a file called:index.html`Now we are in the right folder we can edit the file with nano which is a terminal base text editor. To open the file with nano we do:nano index.html
This will open the file in the terminal.“Thesis 📖/workshops/serv(er)ing in-grid/media/nanoOfHTML.png” could not be found.Tip
Being terminal you have to navigate with the keyboard, and also copy and past by right clicking (not "CNTRL+C/P")
From here we can then add text and images using basic HTML syntax.For the time being we are going to just add fun bits to see it work, as we have some more protocols to write and add.So for now add a message or paste in some ascii art with the help of these links:<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.patorjk.com/software/taag/" target="_self">ascii text gen</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.ascii-art-generator.org/" target="_self">ascii image gen</a>Remember to paste in with a right click!Now if we return to the file online at:<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io</a>we will see our beautiful inputs.prompt
How do we negotiate the space of working collectively as one user?
What other considerations need to be voiced?
When we finish up working together there are lots of things we can do to make it easier to return to our work, make it legible to others, as well as caring for the infrastructure we're working in. This could include careful documentation, understanding how to save and record edits, and exiting programs in their nuanced ways.We've finished working together and now we would like to leave our TMUX session. This is a little more complex than it might appear. Leaving a session using an 'exit' command will delete the session for others, and you will lose the record of your edits together. Instead we can either:Close the entire terminal session window, or use Ctrl-b. This will retain the terminal session for you to use again in the future. Let's consider collectively how to ensure we exit safely, using a door rather than an ejector seat. How does this action differ from exiting other softwares and how does this attention affect our relationships.prompt
How can we form protocols that enable us to care for who is coming next and which Now we have all the protocols ready lets add them to the HTML file with nano again.Once we have edited the HTML, we can launch our page in a browser! <br>At <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://femfester.in-grid.io/" target="_self">https://femfester.in-grid.io/</a>Practising infrastructuring collectively can be (intentionally) a slow, careful and unscalable process, so it's important to acknowledge our incremental changes, achievements and presence. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self">Our (ongoing) documentation</a>
]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/serving-in-grid-workshop-slides.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/entries/Serving In-grid Workshop slides.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving In-grid]]></title><description><![CDATA[These are the workshops that I organised with In-grid members and reflect on in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="06.03.02.00_Configure-ability_In-Workshops.md" href="thesis/repo/thesis/06_in-configure-ability/06_entries/06.03.02.00_configure-ability_in-workshops.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">06.03.02.00_Configure-ability_In-Workshops</a> entries. In these workshops we set up our VPS server with Servus, as an experimental server for us to test and explore some different network infrastructure projects. In the workshop we made space for us to figure out how we wanted to imagine and enact our infrastructure as we made it. Check out the:
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/entries/Serving In-grid Workshop slides.md" href="in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/serving-in-grid-workshop-slides.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Serving In-grid Workshop slides</a> I presented
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Workshop Pad.md" href="in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/workshop-pad.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Workshop Pad</a> we used
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/entries/Femfester Manifesto.md" href="in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/femfester-manifesto.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Femfester Manifesto</a> we wrote.
]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/serving-in-grid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/Serving In-grid.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Docs00 Contents - wiki4print]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" class="is-unresolved"> </a><img src=".html" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self">
<br><img alt="A diagram of the Servpub network infrastructure made by In-grid." src="thesis/export/raw/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" target="_self">A diagram of the Servpub network infrastructure made by In-grid.These docs offer up and share the processes and technical practices that made up the back-end of the Servpub network infrastructure. These docs aim to act not only as a resource to share how to take up and hack these VPN infrastructures for yourself, but also to present alongside this the practices, networks and histories that have emerged into the Servpub server infrastructures.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01_Setup_a_Local_Collaborative_Environment" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:01 Setup a Local Collaborative Environment" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01_Setup_a_Local_Collaborative_Environment" target="_self">01 Setup a Local Collaborative Environment</a> Learn how to set up a computer locally and how to make users, collectively connect and care for it. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:02_Local_Server_Setup_with_Nginx" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:02 Local Server Setup with Nginx" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:02_Local_Server_Setup_with_Nginx" target="_self">02 Local Server Setup with Nginx</a> Learn how to set up the computer as a server on your local network and host a basic HTML page! <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:03_VPN_with_Tinc" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:03 VPN with Tinc" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:03_VPN_with_Tinc" target="_self">03 VPN with Tinc</a> Learn how to set up a Virtual Private Network (VPN) with Tinc so that you can have a portable server. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:04_Reverse_Proxy_with_NginX" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:04 Reverse Proxy with NginX" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:04_Reverse_Proxy_with_NginX" target="_self">04 Reverse Proxy with NginX</a> Learn how to pass public internet traffic through the VPN to a site on the portable server. If you would like to follow along in real life (IRL), you will need these bits of hardware!
Small board computer (SBC) <br>We used a raspberry pi, although You don’t necessarily need to use a pi to create a collaborative environment, you could use another type of computer. To understand more about why we chose to use a pi, you can find our notes here <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Chapter_2a:_Server_Issues:_Platform_Infrastructure" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Chapter 2a: Server Issues: Platform Infrastructure" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Chapter_2a:_Server_Issues:_Platform_Infrastructure" target="_self">Chapter 2a: Server Issues: Platform Infrastructure</a> Peripherals HDMI, screen, keyboard, mouse etc. A laptop or other personal computer <br>It would be good to have SSH installed on your laptop. Most OS have it by default now, if not then manually install following the steps under <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01.3_SSH" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:01.3 SSH" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:01.3_SSH" target="_self">01.3 SSH</a> Knowledge of terminal/bash <br>For an intro to basic terminal/bash commands see <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" target="_self">00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet</a> A Server with public IP (optional) This is to hos a VPN on, but is only needed if you want to host things publically. If you're new to sever-ing and sysadmin, you may find the following guides useful as they explain more of the basics of how these things work:
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.1_Network_terminology" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:00.1 Network terminology" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.1_Network_terminology" target="_self">00.1 Network terminology</a> Gives an overview of terms we will be using throughout this guide in relation to networking <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Docs:00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00.2_Terminal_Unix_Commands_Cheat_Sheet" target="_self">00.2 Terminal Unix Commands Cheat Sheet</a> Is an introduction to working on the command line. <br>In-grid has tried to make these docs accessible and legible (as possible) to both technical and non-technical reading. We have done this through not only try to follow the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.wcag.com/resource/wcag-quick-tips-for-content-writers/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.wcag.com/resource/wcag-quick-tips-for-content-writers/" target="_self">Web Content Access Guidelines</a> but also working with the concept of semi-plain language that Kelsie Acton notes in here chapter Plain Language for Disability Culture in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://nyupress.org/9781479819362/crip-authorship/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://nyupress.org/9781479819362/crip-authorship/" target="_self">Crip Authorship</a>. Acton states this as:
Note on writing: This chapter is written in what I call a semi- plain language style. This means I do the following: Use an active voice
Mostly use the 6000 most common words in the English language
Use short sentences
Use 14 point font
Use “I” and “you” Following Acton, In-grid understands this as not trying to assimilate dialogues into dominant technical talking points, but we approach this practice through critical access to distribute and share the expertise of systems and make the disputable from many backgrounds and knowledges.In-grid also approaches this as a place of design friction. This is where we have made room within and around these hard network infrastructures with and for our softer practices of collective access. In this space of semi-plain In-grid have iterated our own attempt at semi-plain technical docs!We may also use "us" and "we" to state In-grid and Servpub collaborators who made this infrastructure.<br>If you want a light, but still deep exploration of the setup, check out the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Docs:00_Contents#Index_of_Sections" target="_self">Index of each section</a> listed above.<br>If you have any access requests, please email: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:in-grid@in-grid.io" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="mailto:in-grid@in-grid.io" target="_self">in-grid@in-grid.io</a>]]></description><link>in-grid/in-docs/entries/docs00-contents-wiki4print.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/entries/Docs00 Contents - wiki4print.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-Docs]]></title><description><![CDATA[These docs are the ones I collaborative made with In-grid as part of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Main_Page" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wiki4print.servpub.net/index.php?title=Main_Page" target="_self">Servpub</a> project that I discuss more in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="06.03.01.02.01_In-Docs.md" href="thesis/repo/thesis/06_in-configure-ability/06_entries/06.03.01.02.01_in-docs.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">06.03.01.02.01_In-Docs</a> entry. These docs explain how to setup the back-end VPN and server infrastructure that can then host services like the wiki4print instance we have installed there.For this research these docs are important as they are a place where I brought in critical access into our collective practice with the work of Kelsie Acton's Plain Language For Disability. Here I share the:
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/entries/Docs00 Contents - wiki4print.md" href="in-grid/in-docs/entries/docs00-contents-wiki4print.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Demo of Docs content page</a>
These docs were very much our collective first attempt at writing technical docs, as well as doing accessible plain language writing and so I do think they could be improved in a number of ways. One of these ways is to have consulted a plain language author, instead of just referencing their work. The limitations we had on budget, time and capacity oriented us to be able to just be informed by instead of in contact with, but I feel it was a good place to start this dialogue within our collective practice and an orientation to move towards in the future.<br><img alt="The logo of wiki4print, It has multiple off white rectangles, papers or tabs layered together with the letter W4P in pixelated in violate purple." src="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="An image from a workshop we did at Transmediale Content Form where members of In-gird are presenting the docs and a diagram of the network. Katie, Becky and I are sat at a table with our backs to the camera pointing to a screen behind us with the diagram of the network on it." src="in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="A diagram made by Batool Desouky from the front page of the docs which shares how the servpub network is setup." src="in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/in-docs/in-docs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/In-Docs.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:14:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sentinel Self]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png" target="_self"><br>In the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://sisselmarietonn.com/project/the-sentinel-self" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://sisselmarietonn.com/project/the-sentinel-self" target="_self">Sentinel Self</a> project I worked with Sissel Marie Tonn and scientists from the field of immunology to produce this speculative simulation around how microplastics interact with and form tipping points within our bodies and ecosystems. The reason I highlight this project in the background is because it is one where I implemented a different type of intelligent or learning algorithm through the logics of artificial immune systems, instead of artificial intelligence. This modelling of these logics produced interesting dynamics within this artistic simulation, and produced different emergent relations. Interestingly for this research it artificial immune systems oriented a selection system, like immune systems, that centres diversity of output to approach the unknown, instead of refining a thin line of categorisation like artificial intelligence often does. To do this I developed a GPU computed multi-agent system that made room for 3000+ agents (viruses, t-cells and sentinels) to learn and emerge different relations together.This was one of the more interesting configurations of intelligence as it both oriented outside a restrictive centralised narratives of cognitive intelligence, and towards intelligence and knowing as abundant and diverse.]]></description><link>background/sentinel_self/sentinel-self.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/Sentinel_Self/Sentinel Self.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:32:34 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/01_background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/01_background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Neural Re-Presentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif" target="_self">This work explored working with Reinforcement Learning agents, specifically multi-agent environments. In these environments inquiring through practice the relations these agents were able to make together and what where their capacities to learn and represent their environment. In this setup, which is one of a few I made, I oriented them to be able to communicate through a visual layer together whilst trying to navigate a simple task of not touching, but staying close to one another. The visual layer that they produced was their only mode of feedback to the environment and oriented them to form a visual language to communicate through, and one in which the viewer can intercept their communications.<br>This work was presented at 4S 2023, as part of their making and doing exhibition and received nice feedback from the community there. I did end up stopping to work with these agents for a few reasons, mainly because of some of the critiques I make in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="01.01.00_Background.md" href="thesis/repo/thesis/01_introduction/01_entries/01.01.00_background.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">01.01.00_Background</a> of the introduction. These orient that RL algorithms centrally rely upon penal logics and outdated theories of animal and child learning to train these agents, and when I tried to find other ways of relating to them I couldn't. The only ways I could work with them was to execute their code, penalise them until they did what I wanted them to do, and constantly tried to cheat the rules or run away from me. When in search of more intimate computing it could not really be found here. Beyond this, they used a huge amount of energy to train and run the agents, and often with no guarantee of a good outcome. They felt like they were going to cook my computer, and not really for anything that generative.]]></description><link>background/neural_re-presentation/neural-re-presentation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/Neural_Re-Presentation/Neural Re-Presentation.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:32:34 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/01_background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/01_background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[F-MNIST_Dataset]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a data preparation pipeline I made for the F-MNIST dataset. The work came about from collaborating with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://meganbenson.me/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://meganbenson.me/" target="_self">Meg Benson</a> and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://yasminmorgan.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://yasminmorgan.com/" target="_self">Yasmin Morgan</a>. In conversations we wanted to question how we could make a chaotic dataset of hand written letters to form our own dataset and generate a local dataset of fonts with our intentions and contexts entangled into them. This data set explored how we could disorient the standardised norms of AI datasets such as the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MNIST_database" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MNIST_database" target="_self">MNIST</a> (Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology) by trying to de-isolate and un-normalize their indexes and figures by situating them, bringing in their backgrounds and entangling them together. We also left space within the inputs for people to add their own symbols and data outside of the limits of the Latin alphabet. <br><img src="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif" target="_self">This work did this technically by scanning in hand written samples on paper and splitting them into the different segments. In the interface for doing this it also made room for people to add intentions for their data as well as their name and bits about their background. I wrote this in python and used a rdflib to write a custom linked open data (LOD) dataset that entangled the images to this data through semantic triples. This was informed by a workshopI attended called Fermenting Data1 by Magdalena Tyżlik-Carver, Lozana Rossenova and Lukas Fuchsgruber, where they made room within the semantic triples of LOD to form and unfold different relations in data.This project didn't make it past being a pipeline mainly due to two frictions. The first that at this point I had not focused on a technical practice that was very shareable or accessible to my collaborators, and so it lost momentum. The second was that this would have been best served online, as this would make room for the dataset to unfold as it was added to, but none of us had those technical skills and so it stayed scanned/paper base. In this reflection though the work did make room for me to question in collaboration the ways we could imagine and store data in more nuanced and situated ways to try and trouble the ways AI and ML are approached.<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/CorsicAr/DataProccessing" target="_self">https://github.com/CorsicAr/DataProccessing</a>]]></description><link>background/f-mnist_dataset/f-mnist_dataset.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/F-MNIST_Dataset/F-MNIST_Dataset.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:32:34 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-fra Processing]]></title><description><![CDATA[This was a focus group I ran with In-grid members that i cover the <a class="internal-link" data-href="06.02.01.00_Figuring_out_Inflexibility.md" href="thesis/repo/thesis/06_in-configure-ability/06_entries/06.02.01.00_figuring_out_inflexibility.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">06.02.01.00_Figuring_out_Inflexibility</a> entry. This aimed to reflect back on our practice through a scoping of critical access to inquire into how we had oriented collectively around systemic inflexibilities. These inquiries working through a few prompts and points of impact to question how in-grid makes room for in-flex-ability around systemic inflexibilities. Here I share the:
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="In-fra_processing working pad.md" href="in-grid/in-fra-processing/entries/in-fra_processing-working-pad.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">In-fra_processing working pad</a>
]]></description><link>in-grid/in-fra-processing/in-fra-processing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-fra Processing/In-fra Processing.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:19:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Knowledge base graph]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>research/media/knowledge-base-graph.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Research/media/Knowledge base graph.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/05_research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/05_research/media/knowledge-base-graph.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving Cozy in touch]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/media/Serving Cozy in touch.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/serving-cozy-in-touch.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Servering-Cozy  screen]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/media/Servering-Cozy  screen.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-screen.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Servering-Cozy  pillows]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/media/Servering-Cozy  pillows.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/servering-cozy-pillows.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Base lazer outline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.svg" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/media/Base lazer outline.svg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/base-lazer-outline.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy Flow]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/cozy-flow.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/cozy-flow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Serving Cozy/media/Cozy Flow.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/cozy-flow.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/serving-cozy/media/cozy-flow.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[en-crip-ed poem]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/En-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed poem.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/en-crip-ed-poem.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[infrastructural intimacies]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/En-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural intimacies.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/infrastructural-intimacies.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mesh Festival Cover Img]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/En-crip-ing_time/media/Mesh Festival Cover Img.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/en-crip-ing_time/media/mesh-festival-cover-img.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy_Easy_Read]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy_Night+Day/media/Cozy_Easy_Read.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_easy_read.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy_Night]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy_Night+Day/media/Cozy_Night.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_night.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy_Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy_Night+Day/media/Cozy_Day.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy_night+day/media/cozy_day.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[lets-get-cozy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/lets-get-cozy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[interface of Cozy-ish theme]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-ish/media/interface of Cozy-ish theme.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-ish/media/interface-of-cozy-ish-theme.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[less clouds more cozy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/less clouds more cozy.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/less-clouds-more-cozy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[infinite cozy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/infinite cozy.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/infinite-cozy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[cozy-networks_bg]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/cozy-networks_bg.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[a cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/a cloud.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/04_cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cloud.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Cozy Cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cozy-cloud.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/media/a-cozy-cloud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/media/A Cozy Cloud.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cozy Intentions Easy Read]]></title><link>cozy-cloud/cozy-intentions/cozy-intentions-easy-read.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Cozy-Cloud/Cozy-Intentions/Cozy Intentions Easy Read.pdf</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[slide1Asset 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/slide1asset-1.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/slide1asset-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/slide1Asset 1.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/slide1asset-1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/slide1asset-1.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[servpubProjectMap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubprojectmap.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubprojectmap.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/servpubProjectMap.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubprojectmap.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubprojectmap.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[servpubDiagram2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/servpubDiagram2024.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/servpubdiagram2024.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Usersdiagram]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/Usersdiagram.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/usersdiagram.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving_In-grid]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/Serving_In-grid.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving_in-grid.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving In-grid workshop day]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/Serving In-grid workshop day.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serving In-grid workshop day 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day-2.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/Serving In-grid workshop day 2.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day-2.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/serving-in-grid-workshop-day-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SSHDiagram]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/sshdiagram.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/sshdiagram.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/media/SSHDiagram.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/sshdiagram.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/serving-in-grid/media/sshdiagram.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Workshop Pad]]></title><description><![CDATA[This femfester is In-grid’s iteration of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" target="_self">feminist server manifesto</a>. As we rub up against and dance our way into network practices, a festering acts as a place to form intentions and imagine how we want to collectively meet here. We fester as we care for the holes in our pipelines, tend to the ooze that undulates out and sit with these leaky seamful infrastructures. We don't aim to cure these frictions or plug these holes, but to care for them. We ask how we can enable infrastructuring to fester otherwise from our pulsating practices? A femfestering Server . . . . . - Is a situated technology. The server feels out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices. - Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing and maintaining a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affair. - Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relations of the bodies gathered around them. - Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. - Does not strive for seamlessness, as it creates a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible and inaccessible. - Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages we need to abolish. - Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice. - Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. - Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; practices queering client-server relations where they can. - Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. - Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible. - Does not confuse safety with security. - Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity. - Tries hard not to apologies when they are not available, as they learn to communicate their capacities. In-grid is a trans*feminist collective of artists/musicians/educators/hackers working with*for accessible digital infrastructures. In-grid has been working together since 2019, and is made up of a fluid group of people who bring together exhibitions, infrastructures, parties, workshops and research projects.In the workshop to write the Femfester, In-grid members came together in person and online, ate some nice food and tasty snacks, caught up, but also set up their new server with Servus, and along the way (con)figured out what relations and politics we wanted to bring there and how!These are the prompts we made alongside setting up our VPS server with our members. Each step we reflect, re-imagine, and re(con)figure out what we desire each relation, space and dynamic to be for us together. These were done to enable us to find our collective orientation whilst orienting our infrastructures. These are all notes of much deeper and complex conversations, but try to map and inform where we are at.Here was a pre-figuring out of what we desired our coding relations to be. Doing things in pairs / groups Making sure everyone is on the same page before starting work Documentation *so choices can be rolled back/remade if necessary Be soft with sudo Working slowly, doing things in steps, not rushing through, stopping at a step rather than getting half way through something. double check what you are about to do before doing it, as may be irreversible * Talk Consider institutional implications for managed machines Keep everyone up to date. <br>Here we logged into the server through <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" target="_self">SSH</a> and questioned the metaphor and figure it brings of a handshake. When creating metaphors mention what is being replaced
Here we approached the "sudo" command (means super user do), which enables admin rights on a system and for you to undertake maintenance. Here we imagined how we desired to configure these processes and rights.When sudo we should take extra care to make sure what we are doing is wanted by all. Work in pairs (if you can)? For any major changes at least... Should we be anonyms sudo? Or su user to trackShould sudo be used alone? Here we set up the users for the server, but also took time to manifest the figures we imagined being on this server. Here questioning the norms of user/server and individualized relations and how we want to enact them together otherwise.Not users but:maintainers?carers?Member?Players?Collaborators and caretakersit is nice to be individuals in a collectivecharactersConversationalistspersonaInfra as another collaborator not users/usingFistulas Here we uploaded SSH keys for those accounts and then closed password access to the server. This in norms makes the server "sercure", we took up this to imagine what safety means for us instead of security.Is transparency safety? No single point of failure/hidden information or is it helpful not to be able to delete something.Understanding the risks and making decisions based on understandingNot having knowledge lie with one personEveryone should have ability to access knowledgeDon't make ring-fence around particular rolesHow do we make people feel unafraid of making changesBut at the same time aware of what the "risks" areIs it more about learning how to move with caution and careThe idea is not to move fast / gung-ho / "trigger happy", but rather checking and double checking before doingHow can we do things like check a process before doing something, I'm thinking of Nginx command to check if the config file is valid before restarting the server... can we try to research that for all software we use? If we end up making our own tools, can we build caution / testing / care into our procedures, so that people feel confident that the changes they are about to make are safe to do? Demystifying what is safe protocols etc. Boundaries are helpful between the server and outside the serverHere we logged into TMUX an SSH multiplexer (basically a way to collaborate on server work). We wanted to imagine what collaborative relations we desired, but got caught up on TMUX technicalities. . . Turns out that typing exit in a string seems to exit it also Nominate who will type, and check in when people are getting tired. Take turns, maybe signal end of a string/phrase? Over, fin, out! fnx your turn bbzHere we turned our attention from (con)figuring out the server to manifesting how we wanted to serve In-grid. Here we started by returning to the original Feminist Server Manifesto, and reading it line by line together, each member taking it in turns, but also doing this no deterministically and one taking after where the other left off. We also chatted about our relations to it and how it had influenced us in our work and lives. Here we then took space to do a sedimented In-grid practice of free writing to enable all members to anonymously (+ without anxiety) and collectively form our own lines for a manifesto.New things: Balance between caution/testing/care and empowerment
Does not police language, but reads intentions and actionsForm different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.Enable us to practice and perform new relations of radical politics that we need now!Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurityRotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound.Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time.Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicitNot geolocated but bounded/held in a communityNot 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support usConsciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processesBalance between caution/testing/care and empowermentIs accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Does not police language, but reads intentions and actionsUnderstanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Transparent about power and how it's being usedNotes: Opens herself to expose processes, tools, sources, habits, patterns (Katie was talking about this as transparency / accessibility) Does not strive for seamlessness. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible (what is the relationship between seamlessness and transparency) Seamlessness require a lot of labour and obscure the effort behind the scenes.By making knowledge of a system or the system itself accessible, we don't need to make the system seamless? What is the difference between accessibility and transparency? Accessibility of sudoWe then took the original server manifesto's lines and started to align our own with them, figuring out how we oriented in different ways.A Festering Server is . . . . . a 10 minute manifesto
Is a situated technology. They feel out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices our lines:
feeling out what we (both us and the server) need and want from this relation.
Not geolocated but bounded/held in a community Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affaire. our lines:
Consciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processes Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time. care for the ooze of infrastructure, and find pleasure in the frictions. Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relation of the bodies gathered around it our lines:
Composting/rusting/festering, materially bound. Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. our lines:
Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicit
Form different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.
Transparent about power and how it's being used Does not strive for seamlessness, as it is a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible our lines: Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurity Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages to abolish. our lines:
Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.
Not 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support us
Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice our lines:
Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Rotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound. Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; and practices queerying client-server relations where they can Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible Does not confuse safety with security Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity Tries hard not to apologize when they are sometimes not available, but ]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/workshop-pad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/entries/Workshop Pad.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Docs Infrastructure Diagram]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/media/Docs Infrastructure Diagram.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/docs-infrastructure-diagram.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-grid presentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/media/In-grid presentation.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/03_in-grid/in-docs/media/in-grid-presentation.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[W4P_logo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-Docs/media/W4P_logo.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="in-grid/in-docs/media/w4p_logo.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In-fra_processing working pad]]></title><description><![CDATA[This focus group is to reflect on In-grid's collective organisational methods through a framing of critical access. The focus will be accessible to member's reorientation but it will be a time for us to look back and reflect on how we have started to configure our own infrastructure and background away from big tech institutions and towards feminist and intersectional community infrastructures. In this reflection I hope for us to articulate together through processing our inquiry, a few figures (metaphors) of our own to make accessible these situated relations. To do this we will think through how we have found frictions, or inflex when working socially and technically. These will form contours for us to reflect on how we have enabled our collaboration to be in-flex-able together. This interplay being the place we form figures and narratives of access from, and where we as a collaboration have flexed towards accessible futures and away from institutional inflex.
Go over questions for G
Define together inflex and in-flex + qs to help us think through them.
Feel out some topics or experiences to reflect on the inflex and then our in-flex-ability.
What are the systematic and institutional relations that hold/held us in place? From Ahmed - lines holding norms of relations in place. + Aimi Hamraie Flexibile users and soft bodies being conformed to hard machines. Systemic issues around CAPITALISM aside. University structure, jobs/working relationships hold some elements in place, and enable certain actions. Institutions, these come with some privileges but academia/large institutions can be ableist, smaller grass roots organisations that are not driven by the logics of capitalism can enable alt spaces. How we stay attached to these institutions or stay with the difficulties of systemic issues, but find wiggle room, how we make wiggle room. All the other things, like race, class, gender etc etc etc Social and also contractual relationships Time = money under the jobbing job world. And collectivising means we can pool time or labour in a time-poor world. The Catch 22 of being able to prioritise art/research/things that matter for early career researchers/artists/makers is that you already have to have done these things to get the jobs/roles where you are given time for that. Post-austerity efficiency
What are the things that disable(d) us from doing what we desire(d) in that relation? Time, space, funding, prestige, brain space, emotional capacity Dumb systems that's difficult to work with (Ex: No bank options for non- profitable small collective) Working as a collective, that is not a business or a charity or an institution, makes it difficult to interface with other bodies. Transitioning from a group of individuals to a group that is legally definable? Right to work, visas etc wage labour slavery &amp; and chronic health un-diagnosis that both disable/enable my capacity to do anything whether for work or socially, or towrds organising/meeting/ etc What restrains/ed our capacities relationally and materially?
accountability to each other as a group
defining the boundaries of the group. intimacy / maintaining intimacy (is protecting too intense a word), while balancing openness. Project Grant Funding topics (not for this focus group). Maybe we need to be more strict about who we are inviting in and for how long, what the accountabilities etc
expectations from others in terms of availability/ capacity
What does this friction contour?
Wanting to be open but additionally needing some static for contracts and stuff
Too much admin workload on a few people when having more flexible form/ infrastructure
How do/did we process and feel out that restraint?
Accept what works for the moment and being honest about the solution and the restraint
How did we (want to) flex and wiggle towards our desires?What did we do to enable us to get close to the space/relation possible that we needed?How would we have changed or approached this differently? These don't have to be mutually exclusive, maybe more starting points?
Small tech-ing rather than divesting (cloud dependant). Not an issue with the technology more than how that tech is wielded
clumsiness
no one wants to do the boring stuff for free!!!! aka sysadmin / admin / notes
how to make maintenance a joyful and pleasurable space
tinkering with our own structures can be pleasurable
different social relational boundaries / rules systems of collaborating with other groups / institutions can produce anxiety or suck the joy out of the "boring" stuff
relational boundaries are helpful/healthy. sad as it is capitalist logics give a shorthand for boundaries between service providers and collaborators. without going at the speed of trust it's hard to jump into different relational structures. big tech smooths the edges of so we are choosing the bumpy edges
inflex:
lack of joy as default for maintenance
easy of use - hidden politics
lack of community
frictionless - no way of being in touch with it.
product
convenience in exchange for bad politics
scales can be overwhelming.
in-flex-able
interdependence
affective support as well as functional actions . . .
spreading the load of the "inconvenience" of using smaller grass roots cloud service. making room for inconvenience. making visible the labour of maintaining these services. choosing the scoping of re-clouding. picking collaborators (like servus) sharing and bringing back knowledge is something many of us are invested in but the inflex:
takes a lot of laborinflex
anxiety + relations + penal lots of work . . no funding support to do it. . . (unpaid)
needs personnel relations to share
mainly people with mainy things going on
in-flex-able
tic, repetitions, small scales of repetitive. patience and care
not making assumptions that people know whats going on
being generous with time and knowledge.
clarrity caring about pedagogy
clear refrences vulnerable in-flex
Scales of institutional norms
What choices do we have, how to work with resources we can access
Socially relating (differing needs and desires)
how we decide politics and who we align with
capacity for consensus . . . to what extend we delegate decisions or not
CIA's Simple Sabotage Field Manual LOL
in-flex-able
Slowing down
love n care n openness
variety in decision making, bespoke decision making, intuition, trust
being okay with being uncomfortable
sedimented trust. let the chaos reign!!!! too flex for insti - but a form that fits our needs three kids in a long coat pretending to be what they expect. These are very quickly written sum ups, but hope it helps. Do add or edit if you feel they misrepresent or you have q's or other opinions. . . talks about my approach with Ahmed and Kafer to think about crip intersectional manifestings as a way to orient other paths towards life affirmation and disability justice. It takes the crip approach of imperfect manfistings that take practice and care, in their imperfection form bodies on horizons to orient from/to together.Talking about my methodology of disobedient action-research. This focuses on action research that moves beyond the scales of institutions and derives from direct actions into forming relations, infrastructures and imaginaries together. It also routes itself within first person action research, forming dialogues that entangle internal feelings and politics, with external actions and relations.This is a mapping of an internal arc of the research, and starts to re-orient critical access and configuration methods by brining them into contact with each other. In bringing them into contact I aim to see what impression they make on each other and how we can rethink access as a relational configuration practice and configuration practices as material/political processes.(Hamraie, 2017) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6" target="_self">https://doi.org/10.5749/j.ctt1pwt79d.6</a>.Writes about the formation of the figure of the user within industrial design and how this was formed from the understanding that human bodies are soft and malleable unlike machines, which are hard, determined and static things humans have to be shaped around. This pulls from a eugenics histories, and also orient ergonomics as a place to shape people as much as it is machines to humans. With critical access here Hamraie questions how we can make room for machines to flex to users instead of this normalising and violent history. <br>(Cowan &amp; Rault, 2024) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://punctumbooks.com/titles/heavy-processing/" target="_self">https://punctumbooks.com/titles/heavy-processing/</a>Talks about bringing queer practices of heavy processing social relations as a way to re-approach the heavy processing needed to start to imagine ethical, de-colonial and anti-abelist technologies. Thinking with it to how In-grid has our own sorts of processing, ones sedimented through relations of trust, in-stability and care.<br>(Maier et al., 2020) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/" target="_self">https://cfshrc.org/article/get-the-frac-in-or-the-fractal-many-festo-a-transcript/</a>A crip manifesto looking into fractals and repeated patterns as ways to move us beyond the known and into a crip infinite. Here I am highlighting their focus on repetition or a tic we might have, recursively forming actions and relations. . . <br>(Sarah Ahmed, 2014) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/" target="_self">https://feministkilljoys.com/2014/09/28/wiggle-room/</a><br>(Pritchard, 2025) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom" target="_self">https://titipi.org/wiki/index.php/Wiggleroom</a>Here thinking about how to reform roles that are pre-figured or sedimented into relations, whether gender, user, disabled, etc. In these thinking how we can collectively wiggle into these spaces, making capacity for the practices we bring with us and desire to be there as well.<br>(Mingus, 2017) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/" target="_self">https://leavingevidence.wordpress.com/2017/04/12/access-intimacy-interdependence-and-disability-justice/</a>Talking about the need for intimacy in understanding the nuance and care need in access. Here thinking through our expansive intimacies in relation and forming infrastructural access, how we take time, know who might need what, and care for each other to be in that space together. <br>(Gearty &amp; Marshall, 2021) - <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4" target="_self">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11213-020-09539-4</a>This text looks into a reflection on first person action research as a methodology. It looks into how through situated inquiry and one that takes on internal and external arcs of enquiry through both personnel and systemic relations. Here thinking about how we can reflect through these methods to inquire into our own practices internally and externally.Q: how will data and anonymity be handed in the PhD in relation to any write-ups about institutions / relations to external groups? How can we be frank about discussions while also protecting the trust within the group? Do you have consent forms for us as individuals around how we’d like the names of ourselves and/or our affiliations named in any write-ups or storage of notes / transcripts? A: I have forms and information sheets I will share with you via email before the session which explain a lot of this. I also will share any writing up with you for approval esp if you are mentioned by name. All notes will be in this pad, but will also be stored in the cloud and held according to GDPR. ]]></description><link>in-grid/in-fra-processing/entries/in-fra_processing-working-pad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/In-fra Processing/entries/In-fra_processing working pad.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Femfester Manifesto]]></title><description><![CDATA[This Femfester is In-grid’s iteration of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://areyoubeingserved.constantvzw.org/Summit_afterlife.xhtml" target="_self">feminist server manifesto</a>. As we rub up against and dance our way into network practices, a festering acts as a place to form intentions and imagine how we want to collectively meet here. We fester as we care for the holes in our pipelines, tend to the ooze that undulates out and sit with these leaky seamful infrastructures. We don't aim to cure these frictions or plug these holes, but to care for them. We ask how we can enable infrastructuring to fester otherwise from our pulsating practices? A femfestering Server . . . . . - Is a situated technology. The server feels out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices. - Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing and maintaining a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affair. - Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relations of the bodies gathered around them. - Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. - Does not strive for seamlessness, as it creates a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible and inaccessible. - Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages we need to abolish. - Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice. - Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. - Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; practices queering client-server relations where they can. - Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. - Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible. - Does not confuse safety with security. - Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity. - Tries hard not to apologies when they are not available, as they learn to communicate their capacities. In-grid is a trans*feminist collective of artists/musicians/educators/hackers working with*for accessible digital infrastructures. In-grid has been working together since 2019, and is made up of a fluid group of people who bring together exhibitions, infrastructures, parties, workshops and research projects.In the workshop to write the Femfester, In-grid members came together in person and online, ate some nice food and tasty snacks, caught up, but also set up their new server with Servus, and along the way (con)figured out what relations and politics we wanted to bring there and how!These are the prompts we made alongside setting up our VPS server with our members. Each step we reflect, re-imagine, and re(con)figure out what we desire each relation, space and dynamic to be for us together. These were done to enable us to find our collective orientation whilst orienting our infrastructures. These are all notes of much deeper and complex conversations, but try to map and inform where we are at.Here was a pre-figuring out of what we desired our coding relations to be. Doing things in pairs / groups Making sure everyone is on the same page before starting work Documentation *so choices can be rolled back/remade if necessary Be soft with sudo Working slowly, doing things in steps, not rushing through, stopping at a step rather than getting half way through something. double check what you are about to do before doing it, as may be irreversible * Talk Consider institutional implications for managed machines Keep everyone up to date. <br>Here we logged into the server through <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" target="_self">SSH</a> and questioned the metaphor and figure it brings of a handshake. When creating metaphors mention what is being replaced
Here we approached the "sudo" command (means super user do), which enables admin rights on a system and for you to undertake maintenance. Here we imagined how we desired to configure these processes and rights.When sudo we should take extra care to make sure what we are doing is wanted by all. Work in pairs (if you can)? For any major changes at least... Should we be anonyms sudo? Or su user to trackShould sudo be used alone? Here we set up the users for the server, but also took time to manifest the figures we imagined being on this server. Here questioning the norms of user/server and individualized relations and how we want to enact them together otherwise.Not users but:maintainers?carers?Member?Players?Collaborators and caretakersit is nice to be individuals in a collectivecharactersConversationalistspersonaInfra as another collaborator not users/usingFistulas Here we uploaded SSH keys for those accounts and then closed password access to the server. This in norms makes the server "sercure", we took up this to imagine what safety means for us instead of security.Is transparency safety? No single point of failure/hidden information or is it helpful not to be able to delete something.Understanding the risks and making decisions based on understandingNot having knowledge lie with one personEveryone should have ability to access knowledgeDon't make ring-fence around particular rolesHow do we make people feel unafraid of making changesBut at the same time aware of what the "risks" areIs it more about learning how to move with caution and careThe idea is not to move fast / gung-ho / "trigger happy", but rather checking and double checking before doingHow can we do things like check a process before doing something, I'm thinking of Nginx command to check if the config file is valid before restarting the server... can we try to research that for all software we use? If we end up making our own tools, can we build caution / testing / care into our procedures, so that people feel confident that the changes they are about to make are safe to do? Demystifying what is safe protocols etc. Boundaries are helpful between the server and outside the serverHere we logged into TMUX an SSH multiplexer (basically a way to collaborate on server work). We wanted to imagine what collaborative relations we desired, but got caught up on TMUX technicalities. . . Turns out that typing exit in a string seems to exit it also Nominate who will type, and check in when people are getting tired. Take turns, maybe signal end of a string/phrase? Over, fin, out! fnx your turn bbzHere we turned our attention from (con)figuring out the server to manifesting how we wanted to serve In-grid. Here we started by returning to the original Feminist Server Manifesto, and reading it line by line together, each member taking it in turns, but also doing this no deterministically and one taking after where the other left off. We also chatted about our relations to it and how it had influenced us in our work and lives. Here we then took space to do a sedimented In-grid practice of free writing to enable all members to anonymously (+ without anxiety) and collectively form our own lines for a manifesto.New things: Balance between caution/testing/care and empowerment
Does not police language, but reads intentions and actionsForm different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.Enable us to practice and perform new relations of radical politics that we need now!Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurityRotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound.Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time.Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicitNot geolocated but bounded/held in a communityNot 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support usConsciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processesBalance between caution/testing/care and empowermentIs accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Does not police language, but reads intentions and actionsUnderstanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Transparent about power and how it's being usedNotes: Opens herself to expose processes, tools, sources, habits, patterns (Katie was talking about this as transparency / accessibility) Does not strive for seamlessness. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible (what is the relationship between seamlessness and transparency) Seamlessness require a lot of labour and obscure the effort behind the scenes.By making knowledge of a system or the system itself accessible, we don't need to make the system seamless? What is the difference between accessibility and transparency? Accessibility of sudoWe then took the original server manifesto's lines and started to align our own with them, figuring out how we oriented in different ways.A Festering Server is . . . . . a 10 minute manifesto
Is a situated technology. They feel out their context and considers themselves to be part of an ecology of practices our lines:
feeling out what we (both us and the server) need and want from this relation.
Not geolocated but bounded/held in a community Is maintained by a community that cares enough for the frictions of accessing a server, and where these frictions feel like a generative affaire. our lines:
Consciously unassumptive about experiences and level of experience - acts of checking and rechecking in with community are built into processes Can end, is not intended to be infinite or untethered from time. care for the ooze of infrastructure, and find pleasure in the frictions. Ferments the materiality of software, hardware and the relation of the bodies gathered around it our lines:
Composting/rusting/festering, materially bound. Opens themselves to expose the difficult processes, tools, sources, habits and patterns to make accessible these difficulties. our lines:
Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Is open about material/fiscal/emotional resource, labour is explicit
Form different relations of access around both technology, critical thought and crip access.
Transparent about power and how it's being used Does not strive for seamlessness, as it is a bubble. Talk of transparency too often signals that something is being made invisible our lines: Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Is not another cage to hold things in, or protect us from. Creates security without insecurity Avoids efficiency, ease-of-use, scalability and immediacy because they can be cages to abolish. our lines:
Is honest and reasoned about what should/could/can be achieved.
Not 'for' one initiating purpose but allowing space for emergence of uses that support us
Is accessible not in the sense that it makes technology "easy to use", but invites all to partake in "difficult" tech practices, aiming to demystify "difficulty". Knows that networking is actually an awkward, promiscuous, interdependent and pleasurable practice our lines:
Understanding that there is often no one route to the ideals(?) we are trying to embrace but that there are thorny implications and 'seamfull' histories to navigate Rotting and mites and stuff. Materially bound. Is autonomous in that they feel out their own dependencies, relations and politics. Radically questions the conditions for serving and service; and practices queerying client-server relations where they can Approaches network technology and sociotechnical systems as places of social change. Enables networks and their practices to be improvise-able and read-write accessible Does not confuse safety with security Takes the risk of exposing their insecurity Tries hard not to apologize when they are sometimes not available, but ]]></description><link>in-grid/serving-in-grid/entries/femfester-manifesto.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/In-Grid/Serving In-grid/entries/Femfester Manifesto.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20250821111813]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/Sentinel_Self/media/Pasted image 20250821111813.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/01_background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/01_background/sentinel_self/media/pasted-image-20250821111813.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Configure-Able_infra_poster]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Configure-able/media/Configure-Able_infra_poster.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="configure-able/media/configure-able_infra_poster.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[neural representation]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/Neural_Re-Presentation/media/neural representation.gif</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="Thesis/dist/01_background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="Thesis/dist/01_background/neural_re-presentation/media/neural-representation.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[fmnist_dataset]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis/Repo/Practice/Background/F-MNIST_Dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:55:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="background/f-mnist_dataset/media/fmnist_dataset.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>